if you could do something that would
如果你能做点什么来
make you less depressed to be successful
减轻抑郁，从而获得成功，
wouldn't you want to take that drug
你难道不想
every day you got to tell me what it is
每天都服用吗？你得告诉我那是什么。
so it is Scott Galloway he's a public
是斯科特·加洛韦，他是一位公众
speaker and author marketing professor
演说家、作家，纽约大学的市场营销学教授，
at NYU is a business World rock star I'm
也是商界的摇滚明星。我
not done yet the number of kids who see
还没说完呢。过去十年里，每天能见到朋友的孩子数量
their friends every day has been cut in
减少了
half in the last 10 years the knock on
一半。由此产生的
effect here is that we're producing too
连锁反应是，我们制造了太多
person in the world and that is a young
世界上最危险的人——年轻、
brok and alone man
贫穷、孤独的男人。
worth when they say angry misogynistic
他们在社交媒体上发表愤怒的厌女
content on social media they become just
言论，会让他们产生一种错觉，觉得自己很有价值。他们最终会变成非常
really shitty citizens Andrew Tes a
糟糕的公民。安德鲁·泰特
self-described misogynist if a woman is
自称是厌女者，他认为如果一个女人和
going out with a man she belongs to that
一个男人约会，她就属于那个
man is Andrew Tate's message a symptom
男人。安德鲁·泰特的言论是否正是
of what you've described 100% they're
你所描述的症状？百分之百。他们完全
out of [__] control how would we go
失控了。我们该如何
about solving this problem
解决这个问题？
so life gets very hard very fast 25 to
生活会变得非常艰难，尤其是在25岁到
45 and generally speaking these are the
45岁之间。一般来说，这段时期是
least happy years and then something
最不快乐的，但之后会
wonderful happens you find joy in the
发生一些美好的事情：你会在生活中找到快乐。
mundane as you get older and you get
随着年龄增长，你会越来越快乐，也会越来越觉得
happier so I think it's helpful just to
平凡。所以我觉得，
know that when you say something stupid
当你
at a party when you say something unkind
在聚会上说了蠢话，说了不中听的话，然后自责不已的时候，
and you're just beating yourself up you
你
need to forgive yourself and you need to
需要原谅自己，你需要
realize what feels important in the
意识到当下感觉重要的事其实
moment isn't that important happiness
并不重要，幸福在
waits for you what are you still working
等着你。你还在努力什么呢？
on I'm trying to slow time down time is
我努力想让时间慢下来，
falling off a cliff for me but how does
但对我来说，时间就像悬崖一样飞逝。怎样才能
one practically slow time down so that
真正让时间
you can slow time down by
慢下来，不让30年转瞬即逝呢？我发现，在
before this episode begins I just want
这一集开始之前，我想
to say a huge thank you to all of our
对所有
new subscribers 74% of you that watch
新订阅者表示衷心的感谢。观看我们频道的观众中，有74%
this channel didn't subscribed before
之前没有订阅过，
and we're now down to about 71% so that
现在这个比例已经降到了71%左右。这在
helps us in a number of ways that are
很多方面都对我们有所帮助，虽然
quite hard to explain but simply the
很难解释清楚，但简单来说，
bigger the channel gets the bigger the
频道越火，
guests get so if you haven't yet
嘉宾就越多。所以，如果你还没有
subscribed to the DI of a CEO if I could
订阅“CEO的DI”，
have any favors from you if you've ever
如果你
watched the show and enjoyed it it's
看过这个节目并且喜欢它，请帮我一个忙，那就是
just to please hit the Subscribe button
点击“订阅”按钮。
without further Ado I'm Steven Bartlett
无需赘言，我是史蒂文·巴特利特，
and this is the dire of a CEO I hope
这是CEO的专访。我希望
nobody's listening but if you are then
没人听到，但如果你听到了，
please keep this to
请你保持沉默。
[Music]
[音乐]
Scott give me your context what is the
斯科特，请你介绍一下自己的背景。
necessary context that I'd have to
我需要
understand about you and your earliest
了解哪些关于你和你早年经历的背景信息，才能
years to make sense of the person that
理解
you went on to be in your
你后来成为的那个人？
life wow that's a thoughtful question um
哇，这是一个很有深度的问题。嗯，这个问题是
raised by a single immigrant mother
由一位单身移民母亲提出的，她一生都在做
secretary uh lot of my life you know I
秘书，最终也以秘书的身份去世。你知道，我
think the most important thing in
认为人生中最重要的
anyone's life is to have someone who's
是拥有一个
rationally passionate about your
理性而又充满热情地关心你
wellbeing and I had that and the second
幸福的人，而我拥有这样的人。第二
thing is I was
点是，我
born
出生
in California in the 60s a white
在60年代的加州，一个白人
heterosexual male which was like hitting
异性恋男性，这就像中了
hitting a lottery uh I got access to
彩票一样。我获得了
amazing free education I went to UCLA
非常棒的免费教育机会，我在加州大学洛杉矶分校
and Berkeley for graduate and
和伯克利分校攻读了本科和
undergraduate degrees total tuition
研究生学位，总共学费
$77,000 and Not only was it accessible
77000美元。这不仅在经济上负担得起，而且在本质上也是负担得起的。
admissions rate at UCLA when I applied
我申请加州大学洛杉矶分校时，录取率
was 76% it's now
是76%，现在只有
6% and I mention my uh sexuality because
6%。我提到…… 呃，性取向，因为
my freshman roommate in college was born
我大学一年级的室友是
a white homosexual male and was dead of
个白人同性恋，33
AIDS at the age of
岁就死于艾滋病。
33 so you know a lot of My Success
所以你知道，我的很多成功，
whether it was free education coming of
无论是免费教育，还是在
age during the internet age which was
互联网时代成长（这对
incredible wind in your economic sales
经济销售来说简直是天赐良机），
you know a lot of My Success is not my
很多都不是我的
fault so the two things that I try and
错。所以我努力记住两件事来
remember to Define my start and it was
定义我的起点，那真是一个了不起的
an amazing start were one uh you know
起点：一是
someone who was irrationally passionate
有人
about my well-being and uh being born in
对我的幸福有着近乎非理性的热情；二是出生在
America and just being exceptionally
美国，非常
fortunate you mentioned your mother
幸运。你刚才提到了你的母亲，那
there what about your father my dad uh
你的父亲呢？我的父亲，呃，他
you know not a bad man he left us for
不算坏人，在我八岁的时候，他离开了我们，用不太恰当的词来说，就是离开了。那是
you know it was the 70s he started his
70年代，他在和
third marriage while he was still
已婚母亲结婚期间开始了第三次婚姻。
married my mom uh neither my parents
我的母亲，呃，我的父母都不太
very sophisticated uh uh they were both
成熟，呃，他们都在
pulled out of school at the age of 13 my
13岁就辍学了。我的
dad was a handsome Scott living in La
父亲是个英俊的苏格兰人，住在洛杉矶，
which means he not only thought with his
这意味着他不仅用
dick he could listen to it and uh so he
下半身思考，还能听得懂，呃，所以他
you know just really enjoyed himself for
很享受生活。
lack of a better term which didn't foot
用一个更合适的词来形容，这个词不太适合“
well to uh you know a family life uh so
家庭生活”，所以
he wasn't very involved in my life
他并没有过多参与我的
growing up but I feel compelled to say
成长。但
now that he's
现在他
92 every person's obligation from a
92岁了，我觉得有必要说，从物种层面来说，每个人都有义务
species level is to be a better father
成为比自己的父母更好的父亲
or mother than their father or mother
或母亲，
was to them and he was definitely that
而他无疑做到了这一点。
he was he grew up in terrible
他成长于糟糕的
circumstances and he always tried to do
环境，但他总是努力做
the right thing but it was you know it
正确的事。你知道，
was me and my mom was it happy childhood
我和我妈妈……
in your view it was entirely see you
在你看来，我的童年幸福吗？完全……你刚才
were talking a little bit about your
稍微谈到了你的
childhood it was entirely unremarkable I
童年，完全没什么特别的。我
feel like on a scale of 10 100 100 being
觉得，如果用10到100分来衡量，100分代表
the best childhood in the world one
世界上最好的童年，1分代表
being the worst in America at least I
美国最糟糕的童年，至少我的童年大概是
was like a 50 it wasn't bad you know we
50分。不算太糟，你知道，我们
didn't have any we didn't have we were
没什么钱，我们属于中下
upper lower middle class but it wasn't a
阶层，但这并不是什么
Saab story in America in the 70s you
惊天动地的故事。在70年代的美国，
could make you you could survive on a
你可以靠
secretary salary we took vacations I
秘书的工资生活，我们也会度假。我
didn't go to good schools but they were
上的不是好学校，而是
bad schools I had friends but not a lot
很差的学校。 朋友不多，
of friends you know my high school
你知道，我最近参加了高中同学
reunion was recently no one would
聚会，但没人会
remember me my my childhood was
记得我。我的童年
remarkably unremarkable it wasn't bad
平淡无奇，倒也不算糟糕，
it's not a sop story but it wasn't what
这算不上什么励志故事，但也
I would call great with a lot of support
谈不上美好。虽然有很多支持
and a lot of accouterments but again the
和物质条件，但要知道，在
California in the 70s was like hitting
70年代的加州，收入达到中等水平就像中了
the lottery it was the highest median in
彩票一样，那是当时世界上最高的收入水平。
the world what was your relationship
你和金钱的关系是怎样的？
like with money cuz I I remember reading
因为我记得读到过，
that that was um quite your relationship
你和
with money and your your family's
金钱的关系，以及你家庭的
relationship with money was quite
金钱关系，对我影响很大。
formative uh money very early had a big
金钱在我很小的时候就
impact on me because because you know
对我产生了很大的影响，因为你知道，
people say oh at the time having a
人们会说，在那个年代，有个
divorced mom felt like a little bit of a
离异的母亲感觉有点像个耻辱，虽然
not a Scarlet Letter but you were the
不是那种“红字”，但你是那个
kid who lived with his mother but the
和母亲一起生活的孩子。
thing that was harder was we didn't have
更难的是，我们
any money I mean we weren't poor but you
没钱。我的意思是，我们并不穷，但你
know you apply to college and if you
知道，如果你申请大学，
didn't get into UCLA which I didn't get
没能考上加州大学洛杉矶分校（我没考上），那就
in there were no options we didn't have
没有别的选择。
money to apply for me to apply to
申请
college outside of school it was
大学需要自信、人脉或资金，这让我
stressful and but it was also in some
压力很大，但从某种程度上来说，这也
ways very motivating my mom got sick
激励了我。
when I was a young adult and I me being
我年轻的时候，母亲生病了，我是
the only child and some of those you
独生子，那种
know instincts that a son feels for his
儿子对
mother take over and when my mom got
母亲的本能让我感到压力倍增。母亲生病后，
sick I decided all right I I I remember
我下定决心，要好好照顾她。我记得有
coming home one weekend she was very ill
一次周末回家，她病得很重。
and I remember thinking kind of like I'm
我当时想，我
not doing my job as a man because I
作为一个男人，
don't have the money to take care of her
没有钱照顾她，
and that was really emasculating and
这感觉很没面子，很打击我的男子气概。就在那时，我开始振作起来。
together I remember the moment it was
我记得那是在
when I was in graduate school I was 26
我读研究生的时候，我26岁。我
and look I I decided very early and
很早就下定决心，
people I think people who have achieved
我觉得那些积累了
some level of wealth aren't entirely
一定财富的人并不总是
forthcoming or honest I think about
坦诚相待。我经常想钱，非常
money a lot I was very focused on it um
关注金钱。
I decided very early that I was going to
我很早就决定要
have Economic Security I did nothing but
拥有经济保障。我几乎除了
pretty much work for 20 years I don't
工作什么都没做，整整20年。除了工作，我几乎什么都不
remember much else but work it cost me
记得了。工作让我失去了
my hair it cost me my first marriage and
头发，也失去了我的第一次婚姻。
it was worth it is there a risk in that
值得吗？这其中是否存在风险？
that when we become so orientated by
当我们如此以
money yep we I've said this I've had
金钱为导向时，是的，我说过，我和别人
this conversation with if you guess
讨论过这个问题。如果你猜猜
about are we really driven or are we
看，我们究竟是真正被驱动，还是被金钱
dragged
拖着走？
and and how do we make sure we're not
我们如何确保自己不被
being dragged so we can be intentional
拖着走，从而能够有意识地
about living lives in line with our
按照自己的
values yeah I'm not I'm not proposing
价值观生活？是的，我不是在提倡
this is what the world should be I'm
世界应该是什么样子，我只是在
proposing what it is in a capitalist
探讨资本主义
society and that is I think America I
社会（我认为是美国）的现状。我
just moved here so I don't know if
刚搬到这里，所以不知道
society's different here I have noticed
这里的社会是否有所不同。我注意到，
from in America they ask you what you do
在美国，人们会问你来自哪里，会问你做什么工作。
but America becomes more like itself
但美国每天都在变得更加相似：
generous place if you have money it's a
如果你有钱，它是一个慷慨友善的地方；如果你没钱，它就是一个
rapacious violent place if you don't
贪婪暴力的地方。
have money and I figured that out very
我很快就明白了这一点。在
very soon the way I saw it was that poor
我看来，穷人在美国
experience with us Health Care system
医疗保健系统上的体验与
than rich people um I just saw it as if
富人截然不同。嗯，我只是觉得，如果
I want to have a life of opportunity of
我想要拥有充满机遇、
prosperity selection set of mates even
繁荣昌盛、能够自由选择伴侣的生活，那就太好了。
love to be to be wealthy in America is
在美国，富有意味着被人
to be loved people find you interesting
喜爱，人们觉得你有趣，
they want to know you you have a broader
想要了解你，你的
selection set of mates it is the
交友范围也更广。这其实是对
idolatry of the dollar and the impact
金钱的盲目崇拜，而
that wealth has on your life in America
财富对美国人生活的影响
is unfortunate and 100% true and it gets
是不幸的，也是百分之百的事实，而且这种影响
more true every day and one of the
与日俱增。
things I coach young people around is
我指导年轻人的其中一点就是，
you just have to figure out a way to
你必须找到一条
become economically viable I'm not
经济上可行的道路。我并不是
saying you need to do what I did and
说你需要像我一样，没日没夜地
work all the time and be very kind of
工作，把全部精力都放在
have a monocular focus on money which I
金钱上（虽然我曾经那样）。
did I think there's a lot of people who
我认为很多人已经
decide they're not going to live to work
意识到，他们不会为了工作而活，而是为了生活而工作。
move to a lower cost region they live
他们搬到生活成本较低的地区，
within their means and they have really
量入为出，过着非常
good lives I think that's a nice way to
美好的生活。我认为这是一种很好的生活方式。由于
I teach at a business school expect to
我在商学院任教，我接触到的大多数年轻人
not only be in the top 10% they expect
不仅期望跻身前10%，他们还期望
to be in the top 1% economically and so
成为经济上的前1%。因此，
what I encourage young people to do is
我鼓励年轻人
have a sober conversation what do you
冷静地思考这个问题。
where do you expect to be economically
你期望自己在经济上达到什么水平？
and the majority of young people you
我接触过的大多数年轻人都
talk to expect to be in the top
希望跻身前
1% and I don't know anyone who's gotten
1%，但我认识的那些成功人士，没有一个
there who didn't inherent money who
不是靠继承的财富，也没有一个
didn't sacrifice a lot you know what I
不是付出巨大牺牲的。你知道，我常跟
tell young people is you can't have it
年轻人说，你不可能拥有
all you just can't have it all at once
一切，你不可能同时拥有所有的一切。
and I think in this competitive
我认为，在这个竞争激烈的
environment to be great at
环境中，要想在
anything uh you not only need talent you
任何领域取得成功，你不仅需要天赋，也不仅
not only need luck you just need a
需要运气，你还需要
tremendous amount of grit and a
无比的毅力和
tremendous commitment there are some
坚定的决心。有些
people who are so talented that they can
人天赋异禀，年纪
have balance in their lives at a young
轻轻就能平衡生活，
age and get Economic Security I think
获得经济保障。但我认为
you should assume you're not one of
你应该意识到自己并非其中之一。
those people and assume that like most
像
of us who have achieved some level of
我们大多数人一样，获得一定程度的
Economic Security it's required a
经济保障也需要付出
significant tradeoff it came at a cost
巨大的代价，比如牺牲
relationships it came at a cost of
人际关系，承受压力等等。我的意思是，
stress I mean it takes a toll but the
这确实会让人疲惫不堪。但我
right now is because I didn't have very
现在之所以能拥有平衡的生活，是因为
much when I was your age when I was
我
young I mean you're an
年轻的时候并不富裕。 你是个
entrepreneur it's hard to phone it in as
企业家，作为企业家，很难敷衍了事。
an entrepreneur it just requires a level
这需要一定的素质。
of people think we're just so we're
人们往往认为我们
extraordinarily talented that we're just
天赋异禀，天生就具备
blessed with some special skill I would
某种特殊技能。我
argue that you're you have more of a
认为，你更
risk appetite you're willing to endure
愿意承担风险，也更愿意承受
public failure because there's no
公开失败的后果，因为
blaming anyone else when your business
当你的企业倒闭时，你无法责怪任何人，
you know crashes it's very public
这是公开的
failure and also more than anything you
失败。而且，你天生就有一种
have a natural instinct to be thinking
本能，会
about the business all the time and
时刻思考和经营你的事业。
you know there there's a relationship
你知道，
between intelligence and success but it
智力和成功之间存在联系，但这种联系的
tops out at about 110 120 IQ it's better
上限大约在110到120智商之间。聪明当然更好，
successful if you're smart but the
如果你聪明，成功的可能性更大，但
difference between being smart and being
聪明和
genius has no correlation between
天才之间的区别与成功无关。关键在于毅力、
perseverance and resilience take
坚持和韧性。
over I want to continue that thread but
我想继续这个话题，但
on one of the things you said at the
你一开始提到
your mother's she got sick mhm I read
你母亲生病了，嗯，我读到过，
that she you remember the day when you
你还记得你意识到……的那一天吗？
realized that she was depressed yep how
她当时很抑郁，是的。
did that shape your views on happiness
这如何影响了你对幸福、
and fulfillment and depression and how
满足感和抑郁的看法，以及
we how we ultimately end up in a
我们最终是如何陷入
depression did did was that at all did
抑郁的困境的？这是否对
that influence your view on happiness
你对幸福的看法产生了影响？
watching your mother be become depressed
看着母亲患上抑郁症，是的，
yeah my mom was sincerely depr severely
我妈妈真的非常抑郁，非常严重。
depressed but I
但我
remember um and that's one of the
记得，嗯，这就是
wonderful things about our a liberal
我们接受的博雅
arts uh education I took psychology and
教育的美妙之处之一。我学习了心理学，
they started talking about clinical
他们开始讨论临床
depression what it meant and I realized
抑郁症，它的含义，我意识到
that's what my mom was suffering from
这就是我妈妈所患的抑郁症。
and depression is sort of the cancer of
抑郁症就像
Our Generation and that is it used to be
我们这一代的癌症，以前人们认为它是“临床抑郁症”，
CLA posited now people are openly
现在人们公开
talking about it and it's really helpful
谈论它，这真的很有帮助，
because I wish I'd known what my mom was
因为我希望我能早点知道我妈妈正在经历什么。
immediately you know we're a
你知道，我们是
narcissistic species you immedately
自恋的物种，你会立刻
think it's something you've done it's
认为这是你做错了什么，
not about you usually it's about them
通常不是你的错，而是别人的错。
and also life isn't about what happens
而且，生活不是关于发生了什么，而是关于
to you it's about how you respond to
你如何应对发生了什么。
what happens to you and I think it's
我认为，
very helpful when you recognize
当你认识到
depression and understand it and
抑郁症并理解它时，会非常有帮助。 学会
recognizeing other people because what
理解他人，因为
you then realize is that when you're
你会意识到，当你情绪
feeling really down a lot of times it's
低落时，很多时候这
not your fault you may have stantial
并非你的错。你或许有充分的
reason to be depressed but you may not a
理由感到沮丧，但也未必如此。很多时候，这都与
lot of it is about your Chemistry that
你当天的状态有关。
day and also to recognize that this twoo
同时，也要明白“一切
shall pass that nothing a a say that's
都会过去”这句话
been really important to me and it's one
对我来说非常重要，也是我少数几句始终适用的话之一：事情永远不会像表面看起来那么
as good or as bad as it seems when you
好或那么坏。当你
feel like you're killing it when you
感觉自己如鱼得水，
feel like you're in top of the world
感觉自己站在世界之巅时，
that's absolutely the time to bring in
恰恰是应该收敛
your horns and be humble and grateful
锋芒、保持谦逊和感恩的时候。你要
and realize a lot of your success isn't
明白，很多成功并非
your fault you just got lucky and at the
你的错，你只是运气好。
same time when you're upset when you're
与此同时，当你
angry at yourself when you're depressed
沮丧、生气、抑郁，
when you feel like everything's just
感觉一切都
black it's not that's that's temporary
黯淡无光时，要知道，这些都只是暂时的。
and you it's comforting to know that
你会感到安慰，因为你知道这一切终将
that will pass understanding that what
过去。要明白
my mom was going through was external
我妈妈当时的遭遇是外部因素造成的，
that it wasn't because things are so bad
并非因为
for us or so bad for her that this was a
我们或她自身处境有多糟糕。 意识到这是一种
chemical thing this was like catching a
化学反应，就像
cold that was really liberating and
感冒一样，真的很有帮助，
helpful not only to manage the situation
不仅能让我更好地应对
in our household but to recognize when I
家里的情况，还能让我意识到自己什么时候情绪
was down and also to recognize that I
低落，以及我
was probably going to be more prone are
可能更容易患上
vulnerable to that type of
这种类型的
depression um but just being aware of
抑郁症。
these things you know you're a young man
你知道，当你还是个年轻人的时候，我们小时候
when I was a kid we didn't talk about
不谈论
depression we used to call it a nervous
抑郁症，我们称之为精神
breakdown and it was a sign of weakness
崩溃，认为这是软弱的表现，
and it only happened to women right they
而且只会发生在女性身上，对吧？她们被认为是
were the weaker gender and they had
弱势群体，她们会患上所谓的
something called a nervous breakdown
精神崩溃。这就是当时人们对
that was what mental health that's what
心理健康和
Depression was called back then and then
抑郁症的称呼。后来，
slowly but surely people started to
人们慢慢地开始
acknowledge that it was a thing that it
承认，抑郁症和
was no different than any other type of
其他疾病没什么不同，是可以
illness that it was treatable and that
治疗的，而且
it wasn't a sign of Shame so it was
不是什么丢脸的事。所以，这对
really helpful for me it was it was uh
我来说真的很有帮助，
understand it and realize that it wasn't
理解它，意识到它并不
totally a function of our situation or
完全取决于我们的处境，也
an indication of how good or bad things
不代表当时的生活是好是坏，这让我感到很轻松。
were at the time one of the things you
你
talk about in your new book a drift um
在新书《漂移》中谈到的一点
is this decay of community in our lives
就是这种衰败。 社区在我们生活中扮演着重要的角色，
yeah and Community seems like such a
社区似乎是
human thing yeah so I I when I read that
人类生活中非常重要的一部分。所以，当我读到这一点时，
I thought maybe that's in part part of
我想这或许是导致
we're seeing a lot of um unhappiness
我们看到很多不快乐、
depression and these things what's your
抑郁等等问题的部分原因。你对此有什么
what's your take on that 100% um do you
看法？100%同意。你
have dogs I you have kids I do have have
养狗吗？你有孩子吗？我养了
a dog upstairs so look dogs just want to
一条狗，就在楼上。你看，狗就喜欢和
be around other beings and mammals are a
其他生物待在一起，哺乳动物是
social we're very social we you know
群居动物，我们非常善于社交。你知道，
from a young age we suckle we're we just
从很小的时候我们就开始吃奶，我们只想……
want to my dogs lie on top of each other
我的狗就喜欢互相依偎。
I mean we're meant to be around each
我的意思是，我们天生就应该彼此陪伴。
other and whether it's in the US
无论是在美国，
enrollment and Boy and Girl Scouts is
童子军和女童子军的注册人数
off by like 40% Church attendance is way
下降了大约40%，教堂的出席率也大幅
down the the percentage of people who
下降，与
speak to their neighbors is off like 40%
邻居交谈的人的比例下降了大约40%。
if you just think about covid we don't
想想新冠疫情，我们
go to the mall we don't go to the movie
不去商场，不去
theaters right we're becoming more and
电影院，对吧？我们
more segregated by income class the
越来越被收入阶层所隔离，
number of kids who see their friends
孩子们…… 过去十年里，他们
every day has been cut in half in the
每天与朋友相处的时间减少了一半，
last 10 years so we're just not touching
所以我们
smelling and feeling each other nearly
彼此之间的接触、嗅闻和感受都大大减少了。
as much and I think that's directly
我认为这与
correlated to happiness my youngest
幸福感直接相关。我的小儿子在新
really struggled with covid and we
冠疫情期间非常难受，我们
always said well it's because he's not
总是说这是因为他没
in school because the schools were
上学，因为学校
closed for a while and I thought more
关闭了一段时间。但我认为，
than school what my kid needs is other
比起学校，我的孩子更需要的是其他
kids and that is you know the you need
孩子，你知道，你需要
guard rails you need people around you I
护栏，你需要身边有人陪伴。我
think of those Japanese soldiers who
想起了那些
Philippines with orders to not give up
奉命撤退到菲律宾山区的日本士兵，他们奉命不得放弃
the island you know when the Japanese
这座岛屿。你知道，当日本人
rried from the Philippine islands in the
从南太平洋的菲律宾群岛撤退时，
South Pacific they left behind some of
他们留下了一些
soldiers some of them were there for 20
士兵，其中一些人在那里待了二三
or 30 years and they refused to give up
十年，他们拒绝放弃
their commission until they would have
军衔，直到
to find the the commanding officer take
找到指挥官，把
them to the island and tell them come
他们带到岛上，告诉他们
down the war's been over for 25 years
战争已经结束25年了，让他们下来。
these individuals accomplish nothing
这些人一事无成，
they didn't grow spiritually phys
他们在精神上、身体上都没有成长，
physically they didn't learn anything
他们什么也没学到，
after their 25 years years so being
25年后，他们没有什么可以与任何人分享的。 所以，
extended basis that can happen to a
长期独处是
human and every day one of the worst
人类最糟糕的遭遇之一，而且在西方社会，这种最糟糕的事情每天都在
happening more and more to all of us in
越来越多地发生在我们每个人身上，尤其是在
prevalent among kids the lack of
青少年群体中。缺乏
socialization and then this kind of
社交，以及
hyper socialization that takes place on
在
their phone which is really brutal and
手机上进行的过度社交（这非常残酷，而且会产生
has huge
巨大的
externalities is I think one of the
负面影响），我认为是导致年轻人抑郁症
biggest uh causes for the massive uptick
激增的主要原因之一。
so again I like to coach younger people
因此，我喜欢指导年轻人，让他们
every day building something in the
每天都必须与他人相处，参与到
agency of something else whether it's a
其他组织的活动中，无论是
job whether it's a
工作、
nonprofit whether it's Church whether
非营利组织、教会还是
it's a sports League be in the agency of
体育联盟，都要参与到比
all of you and it's a great way to make
你们所有人更伟大的事业中去。这是结交
friends mentors it's a great way to
朋友、寻找导师的好方法，也是
learn how to read the room I joined a
学习如何察言观色的好方法。我17岁在
fraternity when I went to UCLA when I
加州大学洛杉矶分校时加入了一个兄弟会，
was 17 and people make a cartoon of
人们常常把兄弟会描绘成一群
fraternity like we're all these terrible
糟糕的
people it was the best thing I could
人，但这却是我做过的最棒的事情。
until the age of 17 my dad wasn't around
直到17岁，我都没有男性榜样。我父亲不在身边，
I didn't have many friends so being in a
朋友也不多。所以，如果我待在一个把
place that shrunk a 30,000 person campus
三万人的校园压缩成
down to a smaller thing I wouldn't have
更小的地方，我肯定
graduated and it was hard for me these
毕不了业。这对我来说很艰难，我的“
my quote unquote forat brothers gave me
兄弟们”（指那些所谓的“兄弟”）让我很
a hard time but it was really good for
头疼，但这对
me you know you you you you get in
我真的很有好处。你知道，你会变得更健康。
better shape I I remember I remember my
我记得我的
roommates telling me to stop smoking so
室友们总是劝我少抽点
much pot and go to class more I mean you
大麻，多去上课。我的意思是，
have people watching you 24 by7 I needed
有人24小时盯着你，我需要
that socialization uh so I think one of
社交。所以，我认为
the worst things that can happen to a
对年轻人来说最糟糕的事情之一就是
young adult is for them to be isolated
被孤立，
and we're increasingly isolated are you
而我们现在越来越孤立。你对这种情况的
optimistic about that that changing
改变持乐观态度吗？
because the direction of travel is in
因为发展的方向似乎只有
one is in One Direction and then when
一个，而且当
you hear things about
你听到关于
metaverses I'm not I think we have this
元宇宙的事情时，我并不乐观。我认为我们现在很
nihilistic I think technology is
虚无主义，我认为科技本身就是
nihilistic I think the most successful
虚无主义的。我认为世界上最成功的
person in the world at least monetarily
人——至少在经济上——
want wants to figure out a way to
想要找到一种方法
inhabit another planet rather than Focus
居住到另一个星球，而不是专注于发挥
his genius and his resources on making
他的才华和…… 把资源投入到让
this planet more habitable and I find
地球更适宜居住的事情上，我觉得
that nihilistic and uh people I I just
这很虚无主义，而且我
find it strange that the most talented
觉得很奇怪，世界上最有才华、最
wealthiest people in the world want to
富有的人竟然想把
get us off the planet so and then you
我们送出地球。再
think about social media just the trends
想想社交媒体，想想年轻人的旅行趋势，
travel but that's pent up Demand by uh a
旅行确实有所增加，但这只是被压抑的需求，来自
class of people who have the money to
有钱旅行的那部分人。
travel our socialization appears to have
我们的社交方式似乎
taken a dramatic step change structural
发生了巨大的结构性
step change down and I even see to my
变化，甚至我的
kids they are thinking about getting
孩子们也看到了这种变化。 他们想着
home to their phones and they're social
回家就玩手机，
on their phones but it's not a
在手机上社交，但这并不能
replacement for for personto person
取代人与人之间的
contact um you know there's some good
接触。你知道，手机也有一些
things to it uh teen drunk driving
好处，比如青少年酒驾
accidents are down teen pregnancy is way
事故减少了，青少年怀孕率也大幅
down but the number of kids socializing
下降，但孩子们的社交活动却大幅
is way off I find it I think it's a I
减少。我觉得这很
think it's a terrible thing and I don't
糟糕，而且我不认为
see there'll be some uptick because CO's
疫情结束后情况会有所好转。
over but it feels like there's been a
但感觉好像发生了
structural step change down because
结构性的变化，
people now want the dopa they get
人们现在想要的是通过玩
trading on Robin Hood watching porn
罗宾汉游戏、看色情片、
watching
看
Netflix uh getting some sort of
Netflix来获得快感，或者通过在推特上获得点赞数来获得某种
socialization or need for affirmation by
社交或认同感，而
rather than leaving their house to get
不是出门去获得
that same type of dopa hit the number of
同样的快感。
people playing in organized Sports is
参加有组织的体育运动的人数也大幅
way down so I'm not I think it's I think
下降。所以，我认为
it's a real problem and I don't see it
这确实是一个问题，除非有人
recognition of it an external investment
意识到这个问题，并进行外部投资，
whether it's youth clubs whether it's
比如成立青年俱乐部、
after school programs whether it's some
课后活动项目或其他
sort of conscription or national service
形式的…… 征兵或国民服役是
which I'm a big fan of I don't see
我非常支持的，但我看不到
structured means for people young people
年轻人有系统地为比
bigger than themselves do you think
自身更伟大的事业服务。你认为
generation in the in the Western World
西方世界的Z世代年轻人的毅力正在下降吗？
when you think about your kids and the
想想你的孩子，想想他们的毅力，想想毅力
about how important grit is to to
对于
achieving economic viability um I was
实现经济独立的重要性。几周前，我
talking to Simon cnic about this a
和Simon Cnic
couple of weeks ago on this podcast
在播客里讨论过这个问题，关于Z世代是否因为受到某些因素的影响，而比之前的几代人
about whether genz are less res
缺乏
resilient and hardworking than
韧性和勤奋。
because of the influences I remember I
我记得
opened up Tik Tok the other day and it's
前几天我打开TikTok，看到一些视频似乎印证了这
remember one going viral on Twitter a
一点。我不知道是不是只有我看到的TikTok视频如此，但我记得几周前在推特上看到一个
couple of weeks ago from San Francisco
来自旧金山的视频爆红，
showing the day in the the life of um a
展示了一位
jenzi working in in Tech and it's like
在科技公司工作的Z世代的一天。视频内容是：
wake up go get the frapper Cher latte
起床，去买星冰乐、雪儿拿铁之类的，
whatever take the dog for a while
带狗出去一会儿，去上陶艺
class 5 minutes on the laptop pottery
课，在笔记本电脑上工作5分钟，再去上陶艺
class yeah yoga um I worry about this a
课，然后去上瑜伽课。 嗯，我经常担心
lot with my kids because generally
我的孩子，因为一般来说，
children of I I would say if I had what
如果我拥有他们现在拥有的一切，
my kids have I wouldn't have what I have
我可能就不会有现在的成就，
because I wasn't that motivated if I'd
因为我不会像他们那样有动力。如果我
grown up in the household I'm grow my
成长在我现在的家庭，我的
kids are growing up now the only two
孩子们现在也在成长，
things I know I would have had in my
我知道我
life as a young man or a Range Rover in
年轻时唯一会拥有的两样东西就是一辆路虎揽胜和
a cocaine habit I just wasn't an absence
可卡因的习惯。
of money really motivated me and my kids
缺钱真的会激励我，而我的孩子们
don't have that my kids have access to
没有这样的经历，
everything they need and so trying to
他们什么都能得到。所以，如何
figure out a way to instill Grid in your
培养
kids whether it's chores or some level
孩子们的自律精神，无论是做家务还是培养一定的
of discipline I it's my I think it's my
纪律性，我认为是我作为
challenge as parents uh um but in terms
父母面临的最大挑战，或者说是我们作为父母面临的最大挑战。嗯，就我所
selection B I work the kids I work with
接触的孩子们而言，
I can't get over how extraordinarily
我简直不敢相信
talented they are um so the meme of
他们如此才华横溢。嗯，关于“
quiet quitting and again it may be
悄悄退出”的说法，这可能与
draw or I I know in my firm but I find
我认识的孩子们有关，但我发现
that every year and I teach between
每个 我
three and 500 kids a year in NYU every
每年在纽约大学教三到五百个孩子，
year I find that the kids the young
我发现这些年轻人
adults are more talented and harder
越来越有才华、越来越
working and more socially conscious sure
努力、也越来越有社会责任感。当然，他们有时也有点自负，
they're a little expectant some of it I
我偶尔会
roll my eyes you know occasionally I'll
翻白眼。比如
say someone say you know I I need to
有人会说“我得
leave and go to to pilates class and I
走了，我要去上普拉提课”，我就会
kind of laugh like I can't even imagine
笑，心想我刚入行的时候，根本不敢想象自己会
saying that to my boss uh when I started
跟老板这么说。
out but in general I find they're just
但总的来说，我觉得他们非常
remarkable um and again it might be
出色。这或许是
because the kids I've been able to
因为我
attract but I don't buy this notion that
招到的学生比较优秀，但我并不认同他们自以为是、高人一等的说法。
that when you when you're teaching these
我教这些
young people about and preparing them
年轻人，让他们在
mentally and with skills for the the
心理上和技能上做好准备，迎接
world that's to come MH what is a key
未来的世界，但我并没有看到这种情况。那么，衡量一个
indicator that that young person become
年轻人能否成为
a successful adult professional
成功的成年人、专业人士、
entrepreneur business owner yeah I can't
企业家或企业主的关键指标是什么呢？嗯，我不太
speak to entrepreneur we're very data
了解企业家这个概念，我们非常
driven so I ran I started ran a company
注重数据。我曾经创办了一家
called L2 which was a business
名为L2的商业
intelligence firm we grew it to about
智能公司，我们把它发展到大约
120 people and we sold it and we we were
120人，然后卖掉了。 我们公司
very data driven and we used to you know
非常注重数据，
evaluate everybody every year and then
每年都会对所有人进行评估，然后
we would try and look for um
尝试寻找
correlations and while it's dangerous to
相关性。虽然这样
do and no one wrote it down the
做很危险，而且也没人把结果写下来，但
correlations we found that were the best
我们发现，能最好地
predictors of success at our firm were
预测公司员工成功的
few things one they went to a grade
几个因素是：第一，他们上过
school which you don't like to say but
小学——你可能不太愿意说——但
most of our kids who are really really
我们大多数非常优秀的员工都上过所谓的
consider Elite
精英
universities uh two they were athletes
大学；第二，他们是运动员。
we found that um a background in sports
我们发现，有体育背景的人，
especially individual sports where it
尤其
was gymnastics or
是体操或
diving uh that these people just brought
跳水等个人项目背景的人，都具备
that some of the others didn't have and
其他人所不具备的自律和毅力；
the third is female uh they because we
第三，女性。因为我们
had such a young firm uh a
公司成立时间很短，所以我们非常
successful people were women and there's
成功的员工中女性的比例很高。
a lot of studies showing now that women
现在有很多研究表明，女性的
just mature at an earlier age the net of
成熟年龄更早。总而言之，
it for us was and you were scared to
我们公司的情况是——你当时不敢把这些
write it down and I've sold the firm so
写下来——我
I can say it now if a woman from the El
现在可以坦诚地说，如果一位来自小学
gymnastics team showed up it was an
体操队的女生来应聘，那她肯定会被
automatic higher and I don't think
优先考虑。 我觉得
that's anything unusual the uh that
这没什么不寻常的，呃，这算不上什么
groundbreaking
突破性的成就。
the you know I graduate from UCLA with a
你知道，我从加州大学洛杉矶分校毕业，
2.27 GPA I don't know if you have grades
GPA只有2.27。我不知道你们有没有成绩单，
the value but basically I barely
但基本上我勉强
graduated and I got a job at Morgan
毕业，毕业后就
Stanley right out of UCLA which was
直接去了摩根士丹利，那是一家
considered a pretty prestigious firm and
相当有名望的公司。
it's because the guy who ran the
这是因为
department had rode crew and I was an
部门主管以前是赛艇运动员，而我当时也是。
orsman at UCLA and he said anyone who
他说，任何
Rose crew gets an automatic hire because
赛艇运动员都会自动被录用，因为赛艇运动员
you're willing to kill yourself you can
愿意拼尽全力，
push yourself harder than anyone uh so a
比任何人都更能挑战自我。所以
lot of these firms recognize that sports
很多公司都认为体育特长
are a forward looking indicator but some
是一个前瞻性的指标，但有些
of the other indicators you can't
其他指标是你无法
control you know getting into an elite
控制的。你知道，现在能进精英
University now is a function of being
大学，
the the son or of someone rich or being
要么是富家子弟，要么是天赋异禀，或者
freakishly remarkable kind of two
两者兼而有之。
cohorts and then obviously you can't
当然，性别也是你无法
control your sex but I have several
控制的。但我手下有好几个
women in their early 20s working for me
二十出头的女性员工，她们将来有可能
who could be the junior Senator could be
成为初级参议员，甚至
the next ambassador to France and you
下一任驻法大使。你
know a lot of the young men have a lot
知道，很多年轻男性…… 他们很有
of potential but you can just see they
潜力，但你可以看出他们
just don't mature as
成熟得比
fast NYU what else are you teaching
较慢。纽约大学，你们还教
these kids I call them kids that my age
这些孩子什么？我称他们为和我同龄的孩子。
but yeah I I well I mean it's mostly
嗯，我主要教的是
principles of brand strategy and digital
品牌战略和数字
Market marketing but I have a course uh
营销的原理。但我有一门课，
I have a session the the most popular
我有一个讲座，最受欢迎的
session is on I call the algebra of
讲座叫做“幸福的代数”。
happiness and I just go through sort of
我会讲解一些
basic best practices for success and
成功的最佳实践，
we've talked about some of them
我们讨论过其中的一些。
realizing balance I think is a myth I
我认为“平衡”是个误区。我
think the most important decision you'll
认为你在二三十岁时最重要的决定是
survey the class what's the most
什么？我调查过学生，
important decision you'll make and they
他们
usually say the industry you'll go into
通常会说是选择进入哪个行业，
where you decide to live the most
选择在哪里生活。但最
important decision you'll make is who
重要的决定是选择和谁共度一生，尤其是要不要
have kids because you're in that
孩子，因为你要和这个
person's life for 20 years and I have a
人相处20年。我有
lot of friends who are successful in
很多朋友在
most exterior metrics but don't have a
大多数外在指标上都很成功，但
real partner in their spouse and they
他们的伴侣并不是真正的伴侣，他们的
have what I would call a life full of
生活充满了
stress and disappointment on a regular
压力和失望。
basis whereas I have friends who on an
而我的一些朋友……
external basis may not look as
外在条件可能看起来并不那么
successful but they have a real partner
成功，但他们拥有真正的伴侣，
and everything just burns brighter for
一切都会因此而更加精彩。
them so the most important decision
所以，你最重要的决定就是
you'll make is is who you're fortunate
你是否有幸与谁结为
or not fortunate enough to partner with
伴侣。
and so what I suggest is that be as
因此，我的建议是，
aggressive as possible about creating as
尽可能积极主动地创造
many opportunities for Serendipity and
机会，结识更多志同道合的
contact with people that your your
人。你
ability to punch above your weight class
超越自身条件的能力，
and find someone of Great Character that
找到一个品格高尚、与你相投且契合的人，取决于你的
a function of liquidity and that is
流动性。所以，
always accept invitations to dinner
永远不要拒绝晚宴的邀请。
parties uh I think young men should be
我认为年轻男性应该
more aggressive I think young men have
更主动一些。
been told in this environment that they
在这个环境中，年轻男性被告知要
should uh be very careful about who they
非常谨慎地选择
approach and express interest in and I
接近和表达兴趣的对象。我
think there is a huge difference between
认为，以
expressing interest in a thoughtful way
体贴的方式表达兴趣
and harassing someone and if you don't
和骚扰他人之间有着巨大的区别。如果你
know the difference you've got much
分不清这两者的区别，那你就面临着
bigger problems but I encourage young
更大的问题。但我鼓励年轻
men to as uh general cogni or behavioral
男性运用认知行为
therapy to force themselves when they're
疗法，强迫自己在
in a line of coffee to talk to some the
排队买咖啡时与
guy or gal in front of them and behind
前面和后面的人交谈。
them because if you're interested in
因为如果你对某人感兴趣，机会总是存在的。
asking them out to Coffee there's
邀请她们喝咖啡没什么错，
nothing wrong with expressing
表达好感也没什么错。
interest and I see a lot of young men
但我发现很多年轻男性
are not creating that types of
没有创造这样的
opportunities to meet people and
机会去认识人，
eventually find good friends find good
最终找到好朋友、好
mentors and most importantly find a good
导师，最重要的是找到好
mate and so unfortunately marriage and
伴侣。所以很不幸，婚姻和
relationships are becoming another
恋爱关系正在变成另一种
luxury item marriage and pairing off
奢侈品，结婚和找到
with a mate is plummeting among people
伴侣的比例正在下降。
it's it's um correlated to your wealth
这与你的财富密切相关，
because middle inome and poor people
因为中产阶级和穷人，
especially men are no longer are because
尤其是男性，由于
of online dating are no longer seen as
网络约会的兴起，不再被视为
viable mates and they also don't have as
合适的伴侣。他们也没有那么
many opportunities to meet people in
多机会与人面对面交流，而
person where things like smell and Vibe
像气味、感觉
and humor that are some of the magic and
和幽默感这些，正是
mystery of why we're attracted to each
我们彼此吸引的魅力和神秘之处。
other but um what I tell them is create
但我告诉他们，要
as many opportunities as possible to
尽可能多地创造机会去
establish
建立
relationships uh so it's give up balance
关系。所以，要保持平衡，
but if and when you can invest all of
但如果你有能力，就把所有
your remaining energy and having as many
剩余的精力都投入到
uh you know random contacts with people
与人的各种随机接触中，
as possible and also be aggressive talk
并且要主动
to people introduce yourself if you're
与人交谈，如果你
interested in someone if you want to
对某人感兴趣，就自我介绍；如果你想
establish of friendship if you're
建立友谊，或者
interested in someone romantically
对某人有浪漫的
Express that interest if if they're not
兴趣，那就表达出来。 如果对方
interested in you both of you are going
对你没兴趣，你们俩都不会
to be fine you can handle the rejection
有事的。你可以接受被拒绝，
or the small rejection they can handle
或者说是轻微的拒绝；他们也可以接受
someone expressing interest and I think
别人表达兴趣。我觉得
in our age we've uh in a weird way uh
在我们这个时代，我们以一种奇怪的方式，
implicitly told young people especially
潜移默化地告诉年轻人，尤其是
men they're not supposed to express that
男性，他们不应该表达这种
interest what do you make of dating
兴趣。你如何看待约会
apps well I think my advice to young
软件？我觉得我对年轻人的建议是，什么都
people would be to do it all you know
尝试一下。你知道，
it's how people meet it used to be how
人们就是这样认识彼此的。
people made it if you will is that it
以前，人们的交友方式是
used to be a third work a third friends
三分之一来自工作，三分之一来自朋友，
and a third school now it's well above
三分之一来自学校。现在，超过一半的时间都在
50% online so the majority relationships
网上。所以，
are beginning online for people your age
对于你们这个年龄段的人来说，大多数恋爱关系都是从网上开始的，
and it's very efficient but what happens
而且这种方式非常高效。但是，
when technology comes into any sector is
当科技进入任何领域时，
it consolidates it it becomes the winner
它都会整合该领域，使其成为赢家
take most market so whether
通吃的市场。无论
it's e-commerce social media search
是电子商务、社交媒体还是搜索
engines once technology comes into it
引擎，一旦科技介入，就会出现
you have one company that owns 50 % of
一家公司占据50%的
all online retail 2third of all social
在线零售市场、2/3的社交媒体市场
and 93% of search so technology has come
和93%的搜索市场。所以，科技
to mating with dating
与约会
apps and it's created a win or take all
软件的结合，创造了一种赢家通吃或
or win or take most dynamic which is
赢家通吃的动态格局。 这种现象在
somewhat unhealthy and it it plays out
某种程度上是不健康的，它的表现形式大致如下：
like something like this women are
女性
interested in men based on three
对男性的兴趣主要基于三个
criteria the first is their ability to
标准：第一是他们
Signal resources the second is
展示资源的能力；第二是
intelligence and the third is kindness
智力；第三是善良。无论
you are if you're an [__] or you're
你多么富有或多么聪明，如果你是个混蛋或
not kind people eventually don't want
不善良，人们最终都不会选择
you as a mate and unfortunately online
你作为伴侣。不幸的是，在网络上，
it's very difficult to Signal two and
很难同时展现第二和
three so you can signal one and when
第三点，你只能展现第一点。当
everyone has access to everyone women
每个人都能接触到彼此时，女性在择偶方面会
who have a much finer filter for mating
更加挑剔，
because the downside of sex is so much
因为对她们来说，性行为的负面影响（
greater for them if they get pregnant so
例如怀孕）要大得多。所以她们的筛选标准更加
they have much finer filter they end up
严格，最终她们只会
to a much smaller group of individuals
对一小部分人感兴趣。
so what the dynamic is you have 1550 men
因此，假设Tinder上有1550名男性和
on Tinder 15 women on Tinder 46 of the
15名女性，那么46名
women will Express all of their interest
女性会只对其中
to just four men which leaves 46 men
4名男性表达兴趣，这意味着46名男性要
buying for the attention of just four
花钱才能赢得这4名
women so if you apply the genie
女性的关注。所以，如果把“吉尼
coefficient to online
系数”应用到网络
dating it's got the same Genie
约会中，它与委内瑞拉的
coefficient as income inequality in
收入不平等程度相同，
Venezuela so mating inequality is
也就是说，择偶不平等程度
greater than income inequality in
高于收入不平等程度。 委内瑞拉的不平等
Venezuela and what it leads to is what I
以及由此导致的后果，我
call Porsche polygamy and that is the
称之为“保时捷式一夫多妻制”。这意味着，那些在
terms of attractiveness online get 90%
网上颜值排名前10%的男性，会获得90%
of the interest so so that does not lead
的关注。这不利于
to good behavior or establishing
建立
long-term relationships kind of 50 to 90
长期关系，50%到90
percentile do okay but the bottom half
%的男性表现尚可，但那些在
of attractiveness of men based on online
网上
attractiveness are totally shut out of
颜值排名后50%的男性则完全被排除在外。
the market and as a result in America
结果，在美国，
one in three males under the age of 30
三分之一的30岁以下男性
has not had sex in the last 12
在过去12个月里没有性生活。
months and I find people hear the term
我发现人们一听到“
sex and their mind goes different places
性”这个词，脑海中浮现的念头就五花八门。
I think of it as the key step to an
我认为性是
elemental Foundation of any society and
任何社会最基本的基础——
that is relationship so in the US what's
关系——的关键一步。在美国，
happened with online dating is it's
网上约会的现状是：对于颜值排名前10%的男性来说，这简直太棒了；对于颜值排名前
amazing for the top 10% of
50%的男性来说，这还算可以；但对于颜值排名后50%的
attractiveness of men it's okay for the
男性来说，这简直是一场
top half it is a disaster for the bottom
灾难。
half and when I say attractiveness I
我所说的“颜值”
mean by very crude metrics so if you're
指的是非常粗略的衡量标准。比如，如果你的
Tinder profile I went to MIT I just
Tinder个人资料上写着“我毕业于麻省理工学院，我刚
started a KKR and my Rolex accidentally
成立了KKR，我的劳力士手表不小心
is visible in my profile picture and I'm
出现在我的个人资料里”， 想象一下，如果你
geolocated living in Manhattan or living
住在曼哈顿或者
in uh Beverly Hills you're going to get
比佛利山庄，你就会获得
a massive amount of attention the bottom
大量的关注。而
half we not able to express anything
底层的人们除了财富之外，几乎无法表达任何东西，而
other than wealth which they may not
他们可能根本没有财富，
have are totally shut out on the market
完全被市场拒之门外。
and the knock on effect here is that
由此产生的连锁反应是，
we're producing too many of what is the
我们正在制造太多
most dangerous person in the world and
世界上最危险的人——
that is a young broken alone man uh so
年轻、破碎、孤独的男人。比如
recently in the US that wasn't about the
最近在美国袭击Salon Rashi的那个人，那起事件与宗教
fatwa that was about a young man living
法令无关，而是因为一个住
in his mother's basement
在母亲地下室的年轻人。
when you hear about Mass Shooters in the
当你听到美国的大规模枪击案时，
US you know who they are before you know
你往往在知道凶手是谁之前就已经知道他们是
who they are so we are producing uh an
谁了。所以，我们正在制造一大批
enormous cohort of economically and
经济和
emotionally nonviable men and I think
情感上都无法自立的男性。我
it's bad for society I think it creates
认为这对社会有害，我认为这会给
an existential risk for us I think women
我们带来生存危机。我认为，结果就是，女性
there just aren't as many economically
没有那么多经济上或
or emot or emotionally viable men as
情感上能够自立的男性。
Double the rates of college as men now
现在，女性的大学毕业率是
for every one male graduate the next 5
男性的两倍。 未来
years of college there's going to be two
五年大学毕业生中，可能只有两名
women and you think well okay it's time
女性。你可能会想，好吧，是时候让
women it's time women leveled up they're
女性提升地位了，她们
finally getting their due okay but the
终于得到了应有的待遇。但是，人们很快
this has just realized it has huge
意识到，这会对
societal impacts because women made
社会产生巨大的影响，因为女性的
socioeconomically horizontally and up
社会经济地位是横向上升的，而
men horizontally and down in some women
男性则是横向下降的。一些
with college degrees typically aren't
拥有大学学历的女性通常对没有
interested in men without college
大学学历的男性不感兴趣，
degrees so we're seeing less household
所以我们看到家庭
formation lower birth rates and these
数量减少，生育率下降，而这些
things usually stunt an
通常会阻碍
economy uh so I think it's a big issue
经济发展。所以我认为这是一个大问题。我认为，归根结底，我们需要
for young people in general I think if
为年轻人提供更多机会。我认为，如果
affirmative action towards men it would
对男性采取性别特定的平权措施，那将会
just become so politicized and heed that
变得非常政治化，得不偿失。
it wouldn't be worth it I think you need
我认为，我们需要
a massive leveling up of all young
大规模提升所有
people that I think will
年轻人的地位，而这
disproportionately help young men how do
尤其会帮助年轻男性。那么，
we get those bottom 50% of young men
我们该如何让那50%的底层年轻男性找到伴侣呢？
laid I think you need to make them first
我认为，首先，我们需要让他们在
and foremost more economically
经济上更有
viable um I think more job
竞争力。我认为，更多的工作
opportunities I think it builds
机会可以增强他们的
confidence I think you need to get them
自信心。 我觉得需要让他们
out of the house I think it's vocational
走出家门，这包括职业培训
programs I think it's opportunities to
项目，比如
go to college or get some sort of
上大学或获得某种
certification I think it's things as
证书的机会，也包括一些
basic as social service or more
基础性的事情，例如社会服务，或者更多
opportunities for them to get together
参与
Community yeah and I think it's a
社区活动的机会。是的，我认为
certain amount of Education that uh
一定程度的教育也很重要，比如
Embrace some of the things that are
接受一些
wonderful be about being a man being
美好的品质，比如做一个男人，积极进取
aggressive is fine be physically fit and
是可以的，身体健康强壮是可以的。
strong uh I think we're blessed with uh
我认为我们很幸运拥有这些品质，
and this is true of men and women I'm a
这对男人和女人都适用。我
big fan I believe the afford looking
非常认同这一点。我相信衡量
indicator of your success is the amount
你成功与否的一个可靠指标是
of time you spend sweating versus
你花在自己身上流汗的时间，而不是
watching other people sweat any person
看着别人流汗的时间。任何
under the age of 30 man or woman should
30岁以下的人，无论男女，都应该
be able to walk into any room and think
能够走进任何房间，然后想：
of [__] God real I could kill and eat
天哪，真的，我可以杀了
everybody or outrun them one or the
所有人，吃掉所有人，或者跑得比他们快，或者
other and it's not about being ripped
两者兼而有之。这与身材健美无关，也与身材苗条
it's not about being skinny it's about
无关，而是要
being a stronger version of yourself
成为一个更强大的自己。
you'll be happier less prone to
你会更快乐，更不容易
Depression more attractive to other
抑郁，对伴侣更有吸引力，
mates you'll be
你会更
kinder um because you feel more
友善，因为你会感到更
confident so I think ex real phys
自信。所以，我认为这很重要。
embracing physical fitness young people
年轻人注重身体健康，
young people as they've gotten
但过去
years um I think social service and I
年来，他们的健康状况持续恶化，这令人担忧。我认为社会服务，以及各种
think figuring out institutions and
机构和
means whether it's school or social
途径，无论是学校还是社会
service so they can meet each other
服务机构，都至关重要。这些机构和途径能让他们彼此认识，
develop friendships fall in love have
发展友谊，坠入爱河，拥有
more
更多
opportunities um to have not only make
机会。不仅如此，
men need guard rails they need a
年轻人还需要一些约束。他们需要
girlfriend a job to tell them no you
女朋友，需要一份工作，告诉他们“不行，你
need to put on a shirt and get to work
得穿上衬衫去上班；
no you can't get high and drunk every
不行，你不能每晚都吸毒酗酒；
night no if you want to continue to have
如果你想继续
sex with me you need to get your [__]
和我发生性关系，你得先把自己的事情处理好”。
together I think that's really important
我认为这
for a young man especially young men and
对年轻人来说非常重要，尤其是年轻男性。
young women need it as well but just not
年轻女性也需要这些，只是没有
as much so I think what you have is a
那么迫切。所以，我认为现在的年轻人缺乏
motivation no guardrails they get their
动力，没有约束，他们
dopa hit of Addiction on Robin Hood they
沉迷于色情片，没有勇气去
meet women as much because they're
结识女性，因为他们
watching so much porn they get they get
看了太多色情片，产生了一种
this illusion that they have some sort
错觉，认为自己通过色情片获得了某种
of Worth or affirmation when they say
价值或肯定。 他们
angry things on social media that they
在社交媒体上发表愤怒的言论，并因此
get rewarded for they become they start
获得奖励，他们开始
blaming other people specifically they
指责他人，尤其是
start blaming women and they become much
指责女性，他们
more prone to misogynistic content they
更容易发表厌女内容，他们
start believing in conspiracy theory
开始相信阴谋论，
they're less likely to believe in
他们不太可能相信
climate change and some they become just
气候变化，有些人甚至变成了非常
really shitty citizens and we're
糟糕的公民。我们正在
producing just a massive amount of these
大量制造这类
individuals and the scary part is we'll
人，而可怕的是，我们只会
just ignore the weirdo and put them in
忽视这些怪人，把他们
the corner the problem is the government
边缘化。问题是政府确实会
does ignore them because we're very
忽视他们，因为
elected leaders in the US we've been
在美国，我们对民选领导人存在严重的厌女倾向。过去40年来，我们
producing more female college graduates
女性大学毕业生的数量一直超过
than male college graduates for the last
男性大学毕业生，
40 years but still only 28% of our
但民选代表中女性的比例仍然只有28%。
people societies men and women conflate
社会中的男性和女性常常将
leadership quality with height and depth
领导能力与声音的音高和音色混为一谈，
of voice so we will always at least in
因此，至少在美国，我们将
the US for a long time elect more men
长期选举更多男性担任领导职务。
and who do these men appeal to how do
这些男性吸引的是哪些人？
they get elected they appeal to this
他们是如何当选的？他们吸引的是
cohort of conspiracy driven misogynistic
一群受阴谋论驱使、厌女、
anti-government men young men these
反政府的年轻人。这些
young men will always have over
年轻人将
representation in government which leads
在政府中占据过高的比例，这导致了……
to elected leaders saying that they
当选的领导人声称他们
believe the elections are rigged that
认为选举被操纵，
that Stoke nationalist fears that blame
斯托克民族主义者担心把责任归咎于
immigrants I mean really really hateful
移民，我的意思是，这真是令人憎恶的
stuff and so not only are these
言论。这些
individuals uh dangerous and
人不仅危险且
unproductive but what's even more
无益，更糟糕的
unproductive is they will have a
是，他们
disproportionate voice in our politics
在我们的政治中将拥有不成比例的话语权，
because the easiest way to get elected
因为赢得选举最简单的方法
is to tap into the tribal instincts or
就是利用这群人的部落本能或
motives of this of this cohort you said
动机。你刚才提到了
misogynistic content there and um one of
厌女的内容，嗯，说到这一点，我首先
the things that came to mind when you
想到的
said that was Andy Tate yeah are you
就是安迪·泰特，你
familiar with yeah this person yeah is
熟悉这个人吗？
Andrew Tate's message a symptom of um
安德鲁·泰特的言论是否完全符合
what you've described
你所描述的情况？
100% you know we live look it's easy to
你知道，我们生活在一个这样的社会，人们很容易把
your successes and blame the markets for
成功归功于自己的毅力和品格，把失败归咎于市场。
your failure years and so when you have
所以，当
a young man who is failing he's looking
一个年轻人失败时，他会
for culprits and then you have someone
寻找罪魁祸首，然后有人会
come along and say it's not your
说这不是他的
fault and and they start saying that the
错，他们开始说
reason you can't find a date it's
你找不到约会对象是因为
women's fault it's their fault it's not
女人。 错，是他们的错，不是
yours it's not that you haven't
你的错，也不是你没
developed the skills or demonstrated the
做错什么。 培养了他人认为有吸引力的技能或展现了自律，
that others find attractive it's their
这都是他们的
fault and I think it's very um dangerous
错，我认为这非常危险，
and most of it's a Griff the individual
而且大多数情况下都是骗局。
you represented claims it's not your
你代表的那个人声称这不是你的
fault and but by my
错，但你知道，通过我的
4995 you know learn how to be successful
4995“学习如何成功”
program it really is a grift um and
项目，这实际上是一个骗局。
people you know Trump is sort of a a
你知道，特朗普有点像是这种骗局的
version of that right I mean if you
翻版，对吧？我的意思是，如果你
think about what's happening in America
想想美国正在发生的事情，
the Democratic party is basically
民主党基本上正在
becoming the party of educated women and
变成受过教育的女性的政党，而
the Republican party is becoming the
共和党正在变成
party of uneducated men so yeah I think
未受过教育的男性的政党。所以，是的，
uh I think that those types of
我认为，我认为这些
individuals are perfect examples of
人是
trapping of kind of falling into this
陷入这种
really
非常
ugly you know uh blame others kind of uh
丑陋的、指责他人的陷阱的完美例子，这种陷阱
uh gestal in our society I think it's
在我们社会中很普遍。我认为这
very unfortunate I think we also on the
非常不幸。我
I I have no idea what your politics are
也不知道你的政治立场是什么，
Steve I consider myself a progressive I
史蒂夫，我认为我是一个进步人士。我
think progressives have to take back
认为进步人士必须重新夺回
masculinity and that is we have to
男子气概，也就是说，我们必须
Define what masculinity means and show a
定义男子气概的含义，并展现一个
vision why are all the dudes these
愿景。为什么所有男人…… 这些
conservatives so I mean I'll give you an
保守派，我的意思是，我举个
example I'm profane and vulgar person
例子，我说话粗俗不堪，
and on the left they immediately
左派立刻就
complain conflate I've cursed several
抱怨，把我
times on this show I talk about sex very
在这档节目里骂过好几次脏话，我谈论性也很
openly and very
公开很
crudely that doesn't mean I'm not that
粗俗，但这并不意味着我不是，也不
doesn't mean I'm not a feminist doesn't
意味着我不是女权主义者，更不
mean I don't have Progressive values so
意味着我没有进步价值观。所以
I think the left needs to take back
我认为左派需要重新定义
profanity and vulgarity and I think we
粗俗不堪，我认为我们
need to take back
需要重新定义
masculinity I I see masculinity as a
男子气概。我认为男子气概是
man-made societal construct but to we
人为的社会建构，但我们
need to identify it and then ask young
需要认清它，然后要求年轻
men to foot to those skills and I see it
男性培养这些技能。我认为男子气概
as very basic in a very basic way
非常基础，它需要
acquiring the skills and strength so you
获得基本的技能和力量，这样你
can advocate for and protect others
才能为他人发声和保护他人，
whether it's physical strength mental
无论是体力、精神
strength Financial strength kindness
力量、经济实力、善良
intelligence and I think saying okay
还是智慧。我认为应该说，
it's great to be a man express your
做男人很棒，展现你的
masculinity and by the way masculinity
男子气概吧。顺便说一句，男子
isn't just a domain of people who are
气概并非只有
born men women can demonstrate masculine
天生男性才有，女性也可以展现男性
features just as men can Dem demonstrate
特征，就像男性一样。 民主党人展现出
feminine features but I think the left
女性特征，但我认为左翼
are progressives need to take back this
进步人士需要重新夺回
notion of masculinity and we've sorted
男性气质的概念。
we've sort of emasculated on the left
我们已经在某种程度上削弱了左翼
men because to be pran to even
男性的阳刚之气，因为
acknowledge masculinity is somehow to be
承认男性气质
anti-female on the left and that's not
在左翼看来似乎就是反女性的，这完全是
true at all you know who wants more men
无稽之谈。你知道，谁想要更多男性？
women or that's what I find so I think
还是更多女性？至少我是这么认为的。所以我认为，
that uh key to restoring balance if you
恢复平衡的关键在于，
will and not having our party split
避免我们的党派因性别而分裂，并将
across gender lines and pull this
这
generation of failing young men out of
一代失败的年轻男性从
this hole is to redefine masculinity as
困境中拉出来，那就是重新定义男性气质，使其成为一种
something more evolved more thoughtful
更进化、更深思熟虑的东西，它不仅包含
than involves intelligence that involves
智慧，还
kindness that involves strength but also
包含善良和力量。同时，
on the left to say it's okay to be a man
左翼也应该承认，做男人是可以的，
we can acknowledge our differences it's
我们可以承认彼此的差异，可以展现出
okay to be aggressive you know when when
强势的一面。你知道，当
Russians pour over the Border in Ukraine
俄罗斯人涌入乌克兰边境时，
you want some of that big dick energy
我们需要一些“大男子主义”的力量。
distinct to uh uh uh men that is really
男性身上有一些独特的特质，这些特质
important in our society and should be
在我们的社会中非常重要，应该被
celebrated and all of it has been in my
赞扬。 在我
opinion not all of it a lot of it has
看来，并非所有左翼观点都如此，很多观点都
been on the left conflated with toxicity
被与毒性混为一谈，
and there's some of those attributes
其中一些特质确实
that can lead to terrible Behavior but
会导致糟糕的行为，但
most of it is a good thing in our
大多数观点在我们的
society most of it is needed quick one
社会中是有益的，而且是必要的。顺便提一下，
some of you may know we've got a brand
你们中的一些人可能已经知道，我们播客迎来了一位
new sponsor on this podcast American
全新的赞助商——美国运通。
Express and you've got a brand new
他们还为新用户准备了一项
exclusive offer for a limited time only
限时独家优惠，
which I can't wait to tell you about
我迫不及待地想告诉你们。
from the 18th of October to the 16th of
从10月18日至
November American Express is offering
11月16日，美国运通为
new card members a 60,000 Point
新持卡会员提供60,000积分的
membership reward as a welcome bonus
迎新奖励。只要
when when you join when you spend a
您在加入后的
minimum of £8,000 across the first 3
前三个月内消费满8,000英镑，即可获得此奖励。
months this is simply a thank you for
这完全是对您
joining American Express and for those
加入美国运通的感谢。对于那些
that don't know you can use your
还不了解的人来说，您可以使用
American Express business platinum card
美国运通商务白金卡
points in exchange for various rewards
积分兑换各种奖励，
such as booking travel holidays gift
例如预订旅行、度假、礼品
cards and so much more so essentially
卡等等。简而言之，
you're rewarded with huge prizes for
您
just using their card to spend on your
只需使用他们的卡进行
usual purchases and I've had a look
日常消费，即可获得丰厚的奖励。我已经仔细研究过这
through at what 60,000 points can get
60,000积分的具体用途了。
you so if you'd like to find out how you
如果你想了解如何
can get your hands on your new American
获得新的
Express business card than such American
美国运通商务卡，例如美国运通
Express business platinum card to find
商务白金卡，可以了解
out more as you might know crafted are
更多信息。你可能知道，Crafted 是
one of the sponsors of this podcast and
本播客的赞助商之一，
crafted are a jewelry brand and they
Crafted 是一个珠宝品牌，他们
make really meaningful pieces of jewelry
制作的珠宝意义非凡。
and this piece by crafted when I put it
我戴上的这件 Crafted 作品，对
on for me it represents courage it
我来说代表着勇气、雄心、
calm and loving and respectful and
冷静、充满爱心、尊重他人、关怀备至，
nurturing while also being the
同时又似乎
a little bit aggressive with my goals
与这些特质截然相反——有时，我对自己的目标会有些激进，而且坚定、勇敢。Crafted
jewelry is it's super affordable it
珠宝最棒的地方在于它价格非常实惠，
looks amazing the pieces hold tremendous
外观精美，每一件作品都蕴含着深刻的
meaning and they are really well made
意义，而且做工精良。
your book yeah part of the reason why
你的书封面上有一个大大的微笑。是的，
you put that what looks like a smiley
你之所以在上面放一个看起来像笑脸的图案，部分原因是
face on it is because because of this
因为
Arc of happiness that you describe yeah
你描述的“幸福弧线”。是的，
that was quite surprising to me what
这让我很惊讶。你说的“幸福弧线”是什么
what do you mean by an arc of Happiness
意思？在
well across across almost every culture
几乎所有文化中，
the correlation between age and
年龄和幸福感之间都存在着一种关联，比如从 0 岁到
25 is beer Star Wars you know making out
25 岁，幸福感会逐渐增强。 你知道，《星球大战》、公关
PR college football or you know Premier
宣传、大学橄榄球或者英超联赛，
League football 0 to 25 is usually
0到25岁通常
pretty happy 25 to 45 is what I call the
都很快乐。25到45岁是我所谓的“人生真正开始变
[__] gets real years you realize that
糟”的时期。你会意识到，
distinct what your parents your uni told
你父母、你的大学告诉
you you're not going to have a fragrance
你的那些话，你不会拥有
named after you or be a member of
以你名字命名的香水，也不会成为
parliament you have kids you have
国会议员。你会有孩子，你会面临
economic stress someone you love a great
经济压力，你深爱的人
deal gets sick and dies your parents
会生病去世，你的父母也会……
right life gets very hard very fast 25
生活会变得非常艰难，而且来得很快。25
to 45 and generally speaking these are
到45岁，总的来说，这是最不
the least happy years and then something
快乐的时期。然后，
wonderful happens usually in your late
通常在你
40s or early 50s and that is you start
40岁末或50岁初，会发生一件美好的事情，那就是你开始
recognizing the finite nature of Life
意识到生命的有限性。也许
maybe you have some economic security
你有一些经济保障，
maybe you've established relationships
也许你建立了人际关系，
maybe you have these really wonderful
也许你拥有了一些非常美好的
things that are less awful that look
事物，比如
smell and feel like you called kids you
孩子，这些事物看起来、闻起来、感觉起来都比糟糕的要好得多。你会
realize that life is you start finding
意识到生命是有限的，你会开始懂得
appreciate I don't know if you remember
欣赏。史蒂夫，我不知道你是否还记得，
this Steve do you remember going out
你还记得和
with your parents and your mom and your
父母一起出去吃饭，你
mom would like a salad would come and
妈妈想吃沙拉，沙拉端上来后，
she'd stop the table and say look at how
她会停下手中的活儿，说：“看看这
beautiful the salad is yeah or just
沙拉多漂亮啊！”或者只是
admire the flowers and you think you
欣赏一下鲜花，你会觉得…… 小时候我常常会
used to think as a kid like what the
想，这到底是什么
[__] like and when you realize it's so
鬼东西，当你意识到这有多么
weird when you turn into your I stopped
奇怪的时候，当你长大成人，我停在
outside my house uh there's a garden and
我家门外，呃，那里有个花园，
I just couldn't stop marveling at the
我简直无法停止惊叹。
anything like it we have this Garden
这个花园就在这里，我从未见过这样的景色。我们家
across is in the park and I'm like who
对面公园里有个花园，我就想，
are the Gnomes that come out at night
是谁在晚上出来，把
and manicure this thing so perfectly and
这里修剪得如此完美？
I'm not into botney or horiculture and I
我对植物学或园艺都不感兴趣，但我就是
can't stop marveling I wouldn't have
忍不住惊叹。27岁的我肯定不会这样，
done that in my 27y old self but I do it
但57岁的我却会。
in my 57 I find you find joy in new
我发现，随着年龄的增长，你会从新鲜事物中找到快乐，也会从
things you find joy in the mundane as
平凡的事物中找到快乐，
you get older and you get happier and
你会变得更快乐。最
the happiest generation the happiest age
快乐的一代，最快乐的年龄
cohort is the cohort that should be the
段，本应是
least happy because they're not healthy
最不快乐的群体，因为他们身体不好——那就是
is old people so what the learning here
老年人。所以，这里要传达的道理
is that if you wake up at 35 and you
是，如果你35岁醒来，
have a couple kids and you have a spouse
有几个孩子，有伴侣
or you have a job you know and you think
或者有工作，你知道，你会想，
[__] this is hard I'm not that
糟了，这太难了，我 不太
happy recognize that's part of the
开心的时候要意识到，这是人生
journey and just keep on keeping on you
旅程的一部分，继续前进就好。要
know happiness Waits For You in most
知道，大多数情况下，幸福都在等着你。
instances uh so happiness is absolutely
幸福就是
a smile and so I think it's helpful just
笑容，所以我觉得
to know that that as you move into your
了解这一点很有帮助。当你进入
income earning years as you move into
收入阶段，进入
your mating and child rearing years and
结婚生子阶段，
the depth of work and your parents start
工作压力越来越大，父母也开始
aging it's stressful and it's hard and
老去，这些都会带来压力和困难。
if you're unhappy or feel unhappy at
如果你有时感到不快乐，这
times that is normal that's part of the
很正常，这是人生
journey and for me it's it was helpful
旅程的一部分。对我来说，
to read that because I'm looking forward
读到这些很有帮助，因为我期待着即将
coming my way and I can feel it as you
到来的幸福。随着年龄的增长，我能感觉到，
get older you just start finding joy in
你会在一些意想不到的地方发现快乐。
your Ark in your life when was when were
你人生中最艰难的时期是什么时候？你觉得最难熬的
your hardest years as it relates to
时期是什么时候？
well losing my mom was tough for me um
失去母亲对我来说很艰难。
but I think the the the pit for me
但我认为，对我来说，
really high and the lows are really low
真正的低谷是……作为一个企业家，高峰和低谷都非常强烈。
the closest I can equate it to
我能想到的最贴切的比喻
is is having a business like having a
就是，经营一家企业就像养育一个
kid you conceive the thing it looks
孩子。 想象一下，你构思的事物，它的外观、气味
smells and feels like you and when it
和触感都像你。当它
does well it's just like when your kid
进展顺利时，就像你的孩子进球
scores a goal or is doing great or seems
得分、表现出色或看起来很
happy there's just no joy like that when
开心一样，那种喜悦无与伦比。当
something come you have your world to
事情发生时，你有自己的世界要
work you have your of friends and you
工作，你有你的朋友，你
have kids you don't have kids yet have
有孩子（或者还没有孩子），
St you'll find this out when something
当你的孩子出了问题时，你就会明白这一点。
whole universe shrinks to what is wrong
整个宇宙仿佛都缩小到只剩下
with your kid I mean nothing else
孩子的问题。这意味着其他一切都不
matters and you just can't sleep you're
重要了，你彻夜难眠，压力巨大，
stressed you're upset you feel failure
心烦意乱，感觉自己
on a cosmic level because this Instinct
在宇宙层面上彻底失败了。因为
that pours over us is if your kid is
我们内心深处有一种本能：如果你的孩子
failing you have failed on a more Cosmic
失败了，你在更深层次上也失败了，
level because you haven't been able to
因为你没能
protect that kid it's the same way with
保护好他。
a business so when your business fails
经营企业也是如此。当你的企业失败时，
you just it's impossible to remove your
你根本无法摆脱
yourself from that failure my lowest
失败的阴影。我
moment probably professionally was in
职业生涯中最黑暗的时刻可能是在
2008 in 99 I was a young man and was
2008年的金融危机期间。1999年，我还是个年轻人，
Wealthy on paper I'd started several
账面上很富有，我创办了几家
e-commerce companies I didn't realize
电子商务公司。但我当时并没有意识到，
most of it was not my fault that it was
大部分失败并非我的错。 那是
the market and by the end of 2000 I was
市场的问题，到2000年底，我
broke I lost everything through the
破产了，在金融危机中失去了一切。
level of Economic Security in 2007
2007年我好不容易才恢复到某种程度的经济保障，
smacked again in 2008 lost almost
2008年又遭受重创，几乎损失
everything and then my my young son or
殆尽。然后，我的小儿子，或者说
my oldest had the poor judgment to come
我的大儿子，做出了错误的决定，
marching out of my girlfriend so I was
离开了我的女朋友。我当时身无分文，却要照顾刚
broke and I had a son a newborn and a
出生的儿子。
professionally where I was now 40 years
事业上的失望——我当时40
old and wasn't economically where I
岁，经济状况却不如预期——真的让我很
thought it would be was really upsetting
沮丧
and and disappointing and then the
和失望。还有那种
stress when you're a dude with no spouse
压力，作为一个单身汉，没有配偶也没有
or kids you can kind of dance Between
孩子，你可以随遇而安，
The Raindrops if you need to you can
如果需要的话，可以
sleep on a couch I was knew I can make a
睡沙发。我知道自己
living I could support myself myself but
能养活自己，但
living in New York uh having uh what
住在纽约，
felt like economic failure business
感觉就像经济失败、生意
failure and a kid and it's like okay my
失败，还要照顾孩子。感觉就像，好吧，我的
failures are now this kid's failures
失败现在也成了孩子的失败。这
that was really stressful uh it was also
真的压力很大。但同时也很有
very motivating you know IID made some
动力，你知道，我赚了一些
money so I had made enough money to live
钱，足够我生活了。 那是一种
kind of a a kind of a a fake wealthy
虚假的富裕
life I had nice clothes a nice apartment
生活。我有漂亮的衣服，漂亮的公寓，
I could go to St Barts I had just enough
可以去圣巴茨岛度假。我的钱刚好够
money to give the illusion of success
营造一种成功的假象。
but there's no faking it when you have
但有了孩子之后，一切都无法伪装了，
kids this person is dependent upon you I
孩子依赖着你。我
was living in New York it's impossible
住在纽约，在
not to make a good living in New York
纽约有孩子，想不赚到钱是不可能的。
with kids um and so that was wildly
所以那段时间
stressful it was like okay this is no
压力巨大。我当时想，好吧，这
longer about me when I fail economically
不再是关于我个人的事了。如果我在经济上失败了，
I'm failing as a species I'm failing as
我就辜负了人类，也辜负了
a dad uh that was a rough time 2008 2009
父亲这个角色。那段时间很艰难，2008年和2009年很
was rough but it was also very
艰难，但也
motivating cuz I got very serious and
激励了我，因为我开始认真起来，努力
started working very hard and again I
工作。我又一次
didn't see my kids we had another kid
没怎么见到我的孩子。
two and a half years later I didn't see
两年半后我们又生了一个孩子。直到他们五岁，我才经常见到他们。
I you know I try and get home for bath
我尽量回家给他们洗澡，
time but I was very focused on getting
但我当时一心想着让
my household back on economic firm
家里的经济重新
footing again but that was very
稳定下来。那段时间压力很大。
stressful that's your biggest sort of
这是你
professional failure what about your
职业生涯中最大的失败。那么，你
biggest personal pit
个人生活中最大的
pit um and what did it teach you oh I
低谷是什么？是什么让你陷入了困境？ 它教会你，哦，我
don't know I I I think are both your
不知道，我想，你的
parents still alive
父母都还健在吗？是的，好吧，
yeah okay so one of them will get sick
那么他们中的一个会生病
and die and that is the heart the two
去世，这就是心痛之处。
things I found that kind of turn you
我发现，有两件事能让你真正
into an adult are when you lose one of
长大成人，其中一件就是失去
your parents it's just the harshness of
父母。那种残酷
it is so Unthinkable as a species we
是难以想象的，作为人类，我们
have an inability to wrap our head
无法理解
around death for good reason otherwise
死亡是有原因的，否则
we'd all just be freaked out and not
我们都会感到恐惧，
willing to take risk and not hunt
不愿意冒险，不敢狩猎
animals for fear they might kill us not
动物，害怕它们会杀死我们，不敢
take risk never go outside so we
冒险，不敢出门。所以我们
purposely can't understand it we can't
故意不去理解它，我们无法
imagine it you can't imagine that this
想象它。你无法想象这个
person's going to be gone and it is over
人即将离去，一切都结束了，这令人
that is devastating and it it also just
心碎。它也让
really present in front of you but at
你真切地感受到生活的残酷，但
the same time it creates tremendous
与此同时，它也让你拥有了更深刻的
perspective that wow the mortality
视角：哇，
rate's 100% my kids are going to have
死亡率是100%，我的孩子
the same tragedy when I die and I think
在我死后也会经历同样的悲剧。我认为，
it I think it can liberate you and
我认为它可以让你获得解脱，让你
realize that said okay if I feel
意识到，好吧，如果我感到
embarrassed if I feel scared about risks
尴尬，如果我对风险感到害怕，
if I'm beating myself up over a mistake
我一直在自责自己犯的错误，
I made you know what it really doesn't
你知道吗？其实没
matter that much you should be kinder to
那么重要。你应该对
yourself you should be more forgiving
自己好一点，应该更宽容一些。我
there's great work by my colleague at
在纽约大学的同事亚当·阿尔特（Adam Alter）做了一项很棒的研究，
he surveys people who are weeks from the
他调查了那些生命垂危的人，
end and they have a lot of regrets they
他们有很多遗憾。他们
they wish they'd live the life they want
希望自己能过上想要的生活，比如
to live whether it was being more open
更坦诚地
about their sexuality being who they
面对自己的性取向，选择自己
wanted to be with going to the career
想在一起的人，从事
they wanted to go with they were living
自己想从事的职业。他们后悔自己曾经
their lives for other people is a huge
为了别人
regret or Society they wish they'd
或社会而活，这让他们感到无比遗憾。他们希望自己能
stayed in better contact with friends
和朋友保持更好的联系。
but more than anything their number one
但最让他们
regret is they wish they'd been less
后悔的，还是
harsh on themselves and that is again
对自己少一些苛责。这再次说明，
life isn't about what happens to you
人生不在于发生了什么，而在于你
it's how you respond to what happens to
如何应对。
you and when someone dies and you
当有人去世，你
realize the finite nature of life and
意识到生命的有限性，意识到
that we all have the same end coming I
我们最终都会走向同一个终点，我
think it's liberating because what you
认为这是一种解脱。因为你会意识到，即使
in a board meeting even when you have a
在董事会上说了蠢话，即使你的
business fail when you pick a stock and
公司失败了，即使你选中的股票被
it gets cut half in two weeks and you're
砍价一半，你最终都会走向死亡。 两周后，你就会因为
something stupid at a party when you say
在聚会上说了蠢话、
something unkind unwittingly and you're
无意中说了些不中听的话而自责不已，你会想：
just like Jesus what was I think and
天哪，我当时到底在想什么？
you're just beating yourself up realize
你会不停地责备自己。但你要明白，
it's the person you're worried about
你真正担心的是别人对
what they think of you your situation
你的看法。你的处境会过得
it's going to go really fast and it's
很快，一切都会
going to be over and all you're going to
结束，你最终拥有的只有那些
have is the people that miss you so you
想念你的人。所以，
don't you need to forgive yourself and
你需要原谅自己，
you need to
你需要
realize what feels important in the
明白，当下感觉重要的事其实
moment isn't that important and I found
并不那么重要。我发现
it very liberating I was devastated
这很能解脱。
losing a parent and was really my only
失去父母让我痛苦万分，而他几乎是我唯一的
parent but at the same time it just gave
亲人。但与此同时，这也让我对人生有了
me a lot of perspective and then I think
很多新的感悟。我觉得
the second moment in your life you start
人生中第二个真正开始
to grow up is when you have a kid
成长的时刻就是有了孩子。在
because up until that moment and I'm
那之前，我天生是个
naturally a selfish person it comes it
自私的人，为人父母
comes very easily to me but it's the
对我来说很容易，但这是
first time in your life you're more
人生中第一次你会更加
concerned with someone else's
关心别人的
well-being and it's it's it's a strange
幸福。
sense to want someone else to be more
希望别人更关心自己，这是一种很奇妙的感觉。
than yours I mean truly more concerned
比起自己的幸福，我更关心别人的幸福，
and it's somewhat liberating when I was
这在某种程度上是一种解脱。
your age on Friday I'd start getting
我像你这么大的时候，周五就开始
stressed like what fabulous people am I
焦虑，比如我跟哪些很棒的人
hanging out with what amazing thing am I
在一起？我做了哪些了不起的事？我
doing how can I hang around more
怎样才能和更
interesting and hotter people how can I
有趣、更漂亮的人在一起？我怎样才能
have better experiences sex more sex
有更好的体验？怎样才能和更
with hotter people make more money make
漂亮的人发生更多性关系？怎样才能赚
more money now it's like okay we got
更多钱？现在，我的注意力都集中在别人身上了，比如
soccer practice Saturday morning we got
周六早上有足球训练，我们还有孩子一起
a play dates out it's all of a sudden
玩。真的，一切都只关乎
just about them and for the first few
他们了。头
few years that takes some
几年需要
adapting but what you find I find it's
适应，但你会发现，
relaxing now to be more focused on
现在把注意力放在
someone else I find is is is relaxing
别人身上反而更放松，也更有
and rewarding instead of just all you
成就感，而不是总是只关注自己。
all the time right so losing someone and
所以，失去某人和
gaining someone I think are the kind of
得到某人，我认为都是
key moments where you sort of uh grow up
成长的关键时刻。
I mean losing your parent is something
失去父母是
that happens to everybody some the
每个人都会经历的事，至于
economic strain I have most people would
经济压力，大多数人都会
pray for but personal troughs uh I've
祈祷能摆脱，但个人低谷嘛，我目前为止真的很
been really blessed so far you talked a
幸运。你刚才提到了
little bit there about self-doubt yeah
自我怀疑，嗯，你呢？
um do you do you struggle with
你也会
self-doubt oh yeah I have a huge
自我怀疑吗？哦，是的，我有很严重的
impostor syndrome but I think it's
冒名顶替综合症，但我认为这是
healthy and I think most people have it
健康的，而且我觉得大多数人都有。
I think um yeah I I sure uh every time
嗯，是的，我肯定，每次
I've raised money I've thought I was
我筹集资金的时候，我都会觉得自己在
fooling them committing fraud like oh
骗他们，在搞诈骗，比如，
God I just raised $37 million from my
天哪，我刚从我的教育科技创业公司筹集了3700万美元，
edtech startup what were they thinking
他们到底在想什么？
you know what were they thinking um I
你知道，他们到底在想什么？嗯，我
don't you know I weird things like uh I
不知道，你知道，我有一些奇怪的想法，比如，我
I get I'm sure you get fan mail or uh if
收到粉丝来信，或者，如果
people who listen my podcast or want to
有人听我的播客，或者
meet me or have dinner with me I don't
想见我，或者想和我一起吃饭，我都不
like to do it because I always find
喜欢，因为我总是觉得
they're going to be disappointed that
他们会失望，他们
the person they think I am I'm just not
想象中的我其实没那么
that interesting or that cool um I I
有趣，也没那么酷。嗯，我
always worry that at the end of the day
总是担心，到头来，
my natural state will be to be broken
我的本性会是
alone that that's kind of like what my
孤独地崩溃，这有点像我的
personality traits were they'll lead me
性格特征，它们会把我引向……
um I have those fears every day I have
嗯，我每天都有这些恐惧，我有很
huge impostor
严重的冒名顶替
syndrome um yeah so but again it it's
综合症。嗯，是的，所以，但话说回来，它也是
motivating it's like well okay prove
动力，就像…… 好吧，那就证明你
yourself and them wrong so I I wouldn't
自己和他们都错了。我不会这样
describe myself I'm not a I'm I'm I'm
形容自己，我不是那种……我……我……我……我……
I'm I'm confident on certain levels but
我在某些方面确实很自信，但
I always feel like a little bit like
我总觉得，
every time I have an achievement I've
每次取得成就的时候，我
like kind of fooled everybody do you
好像骗过了所有人。你
know where that comes from because I I
知道这种感觉从何而来吗？因为我
I'm not sure if that's everybody I sit
不确定是不是每个人都这样，我身边的
here with a lot of people so I see a
人很多，所以我看到的
variance yeah I don't know yeah I really
情况也各不相同。是的，我不知道，是的，我真的不
don't know I don't know
知道，我不知道……
where um I don't know where it comes
我不知道这种感觉从何而来，
from but yeah I definitely have
但我耳边肯定有个声音在低语，
something whispering in my ear like yeah
比如“
that you you temp you fooled them
你他妈在骗谁呢？”。是的，你只是暂时骗过了他们，
temporarily but it's all going to come
但一切都会
crashing down yeah I have that when I
崩塌的。是的，我
was reading through a lot of things
读过
you'd said about yourself you you also
你很多关于自己的话，你
had called yourself an [__] a few
也曾几次称自己是混蛋。
mhm what do you mean by that and why
嗯，你这话是什么意思？你为什么觉得自己是
[__] uh yeah simp someone who wasn't
混蛋？呃，舔狗，不
kind someone who put their own needs
友善的人，把自己的需求放在
ahead of other people I wasn't very kind
别人需求之上的人。
to my first wife I should have been as
我对第一任妻子不太好，作为
an early manager I should have been
一名早期的管理者，我应该
kinder to my employees yeah an
对我的员工更友善一些。是的，我当时是个
[__] why why or how I don't know I I
混蛋，为什么？为什么？或者怎么会这样？我不知道。我
guess because I could or I don't know I
猜是因为我能做到，或者我不知道。我
like that think that I've gotten better
喜欢这样。
as I've gotten older I think in America
我觉得随着年龄的增长，我有所改进。我认为在美国，
this um at least and it's changing in
至少在某种程度上，这种现象正在改变。
the world I grew up when I think it's
我成长的那个年代，我认为这种改变始于
kind of started with Steve
史蒂夫·
Jobs you know here's a guy who I think
乔布斯。你知道，这个人……我认为
American Business that if you're
美国商界存在一种不幸的观念：如果你有
talented and super nice you're talented
才华又非常友善，你就是有才华的；
if you're talented and a bit of an
如果你有才华但有点
[__] you're a genius
混蛋，你就是个天才。在当时，
it was seen as leadership to be in a
领导力被视为在
room and and get angry or point out the
房间里发火、指出
problems or dress somebody down I think
问题或训斥别人。我认为
last 10 years but everybody was trying
过去十年里，这种情况已经有所改善，但每个人都想
to be Steve Jobs and there's no getting
成为史蒂夫·乔布斯，这是无法回避的。
around it he was cruel at work he denied
他在工作中很残酷，
his own blood under oath to avoid child
为了逃避支付子女抚养费，他甚至在宣誓后否认自己的血缘关系，
support payments while it was worth a
而当时他的公司价值高达
quarter of a billion dollars and that's
2.5亿美元。 他就是
the Jesus Christ of our information age
我们信息时代
economy this was not a kind
经济的耶稣基督，他可不是个和善的
man and so in the Tech Community in the
人。所以在90年代的科技圈，
was uh kind of rewarded to be you know
你得是个斗士，说话刻薄才行，这似乎是一种奖励。
harsh and I think a lot of that has
我觉得现在很多事情都
changed for the better you realize and I
变好了，你会意识到这一点。
just as you get older you're just
就像你年纪大了，你就会变得
younger you're selfish and I think I've
年轻，你会变得自私。我想我
gotten some early
早年取得了一些
success so I I don't think I realize the
成功，所以我不认为我意识到
extent to which luck played a role in
运气在其中扮演了多大的角色。
that but I've gotten better um I'm you
但我确实变得更好了，嗯，我没那么
know less of an [__] what has allowed
混蛋了。是什么让
you to increase your self-awareness you
你提高了自我认知呢？你年纪大了，你就会……
just get older you just get you know you
你知道，你年纪大了，你会意识到这一点。
just get older you realize I remember I
我记得有
had one moment and it I was at a I was
一次，我在一个
in a meeting I run my own companies yeah
会议上——我经营着自己的公司——是的，在
before I joined NYU and I remember like
我加入纽约大学之前——我记得当时
just nothing that big a deal but this
没什么大不了的，但这
guy was presenting and he was had some
个人正在做报告，他有一些
slides and I'm like I'm might go back
幻灯片，我想，我可能会……
I'm like your slides make no [__]
我当时就想，你的幻灯片简直莫名其妙，
sense I'm like just don't don't get us
我心想，别把我们都叫到
all in a room and present this garbage
房间里来，就为了展示这些垃圾，垃圾！就这么简单，我就是这么说的。
those exact words and he finished the
他
presentation and then we're all you know
讲完了，然后我们都知道，
afterwards and I went to the men's room
之后我去男厕所，
and he was in the men's room and he was
他也在里面，就在
next to me at the Ural urinal and I saw
我旁边的小便池边。我看到
his hand shaking he was so rattled by
他的手在抖，他被刚才那件事吓坏了，好像是
the thing that he had like a small py or
尿失禁之
little bit more self-aware and kind of
类的。我记得当时我在想，我终于到了可以稍微自省一下的年纪了，开始反思，
success if you just make other people
如果成功只是让别人
feel like [__] like what's the a point
感觉糟糕，那这一切又有什么意义呢？
and I thought why did I do that and some
我当时想，我为什么要那样做？一部分原因是，我想
of it was to communicate that this was
表达这种行为是
unacceptable and it was the data that
不可接受的，
this person was presenting was
这个人展示的数据是
unacceptable but it would have been just
不可接受的，但也有一部分原因是，
but part of it was for me to take the
我想借此
opportunity to elevate my own
机会贬低别人，抬高自己的
stature by diminishing someone else's
地位。 别人的，
and that's entirely wrong and what you
这完全是错的。
realize as you get older is that you
随着年龄增长，你会意识到，你
don't need to diminish other people's
不需要贬低别人的
status to get to the same point I should
地位才能达到同样的目标。我应该把
have taken him aside and said come on
他拉到一边，告诉他：“
man data was you can do better than that
伙计，数据是这样的，你可以做得更好。
this is what was wrong with it this is
这就是问题所在，这就是
what how I think you should present the
我认为你应该呈现
data realize that you're presenting to a
数据的方式。你要明白，你是在向
group of people who are going to notice
一群人做演示，他们会注意到
that data contradicts the data on the
这些数据与下一张幻灯片上的数据相矛盾。然而，我却……
next slide and instead uh uh my need to
呃……我需要
feel I don't know important or whatever
感觉自己很重要什么的，把
put my own needs ahead of theirs I think
自己的需求放在了他们之上。我认为这种情况很普遍，
there's a lot of that I don't think I
我
don't think it's a unique attribute uh
不认为这是我独有的特质。
but I I'd like to think that I've
但我希望我已经从
starched most of most of that out of my
我的
professional life I think you just get
职业生涯中彻底摒弃了大部分这种想法。我认为随着年龄
older uh hopefully you get Kinder you
增长，你会变得更
self-aware but oh yeah I look back on my
友善，更有自知之明。但是，是的，回顾我的
career there's a lot I'm not proud of
职业生涯，有很多事情我并不引以为豪。
what are you still working on
你个人还在努力改进什么？活在当下。你
personally uh being present you know you
知道，你会对
regret and upset about the past anxiety
过去感到后悔和沮丧。”
about the
对未来的焦虑让我完全脱离了当下。我
trying to enjoy my sons at boarding
努力享受儿子们在寄宿
school the most difficult thing about
学校的时光，但
moving here is I come home my boy's not
搬到这里最难受的就是回家后儿子不在家，我
there my my 15-year-old that's really
15岁的儿子不在家，这对
strange for me you'll see when your kids
我来说真的很奇怪。你会发现，孩子们
are around they become a limb like when
在身边的时候，他们就像你的肢体一样，而当
you're not around your kids you feel as
你不在他们身边时，你会感觉好像有
if something's wrong I mean the first
什么地方不对劲。我的意思是，
the first day away from them is amazing
离开他们的第一天感觉很棒，但
and then it gets awful you're like oh
之后就变得很糟糕。你会想，哦，
God this is wonderful I can sleep in you
天哪，这太好了，我可以睡懒觉了。你
know I like I used to like business
知道，我以前很喜欢
travel especially when their babies
出差，尤其是有孩子的时候——
babies are tough but now you feel like
孩子很辛苦——但现在你会感觉
you're like you're like walking around
自己好像失去了一条胳膊腿，这很
without a limb is it's just weird and my
奇怪。我的
son's in boarding school here and so
儿子在这里的寄宿学校读书，所以
coming home and not having him home is
回家后他不在家真的非常非常
just very uh very strange so when he was
奇怪。
home yesterday he's only home for a day
昨天他回家了，但他周末只在家待一天
and a half on the weekends trying to be
半。我努力让自己活在当下，努力让自己专注于眼前的事情，但这对我来说
I have a tough time one of my talents as
很难。
an entrepreneur I think is that I'm
我认为我作为企业家的一个天赋就是我
always thinking about work and focused
总是想着工作，专注
on [__] so when I show up Monday morning
于…… 所以周一早上我到公司的时候，其实已经有点
I've kind of got a head start because
领先一步了，因为
I'm thinking about problems I'm thinking
我在思考问题，在思考各种
about stuff but the problem is you're
事情。但问题是，你
not that present and it's very hard to
没法真正活在当下，很难
balance those two because it's so
平衡这两者，因为
competitive I mean I would imagine I
竞争太激烈了。我的意思是，我
look around I I I know your success I
环顾四周，我知道你的成功，我想
would imagine you're constantly thinking
你肯定一直在想着
about work right thinking about new new
工作，想着如何
ways to improve things people you can
改进，想着可以联系的人，想着应该发
reach out to emails you should send to
邮件
encourage people you know just
鼓励别人，想着你认识的人，总之一直在
constantly think about it once you have
想着这些。一旦有了
kids it's very hard to manage that
孩子，就很难保持这种
balance because you want to be present
平衡了，因为你想全身心投入。
so I'm trying to be present also
所以我也在努力让自己活在当下，同时也在
I'm trying to slow time down time is
努力让时间慢下来。
falling off a cliff for me um I have a
对我来说，时间就像悬崖一样飞逝。嗯，我
chat group with my college friends it
和大学朋友们有个聊天群，
yesterday you know when we were in
昨天我们还在上
college it's it's just flown by the last
大学呢。过去的
30 years which means it's going to go
30年过得飞快，这意味着时间会过得
even faster and I'm going to be 87 so
更快，我都要87岁了。所以我在
trying to slow time down trying to be
努力让时间慢下来，努力让自己
more present that's what I'm working on
更活在当下。这就是我正在努力的。嗯，嗯，
and uh uh you just trying to be kinder I
我想你也应该试着对别人更友善一些。
think I think everyone should from day
我觉得每个人从一开始就应该
one just think okay how can I be more
思考：怎样才能更
kind how do we slow time down my my uh
友善一些？怎样才能让时间慢下来？嗯，
my friend asked me the other day what my
我朋友前几天问我，如果能拥有
superpower would be and that's what I
超能力，我会选择什么？
said I said I wish I could pause time
我说，我希望能够暂停时间。我知道这个
answer but I was like because then I
答案可能有点不妥，但我当时的想法是，那样我就可以
could get my work done yeah yeah and
完成工作，
continue with with my life and then
继续我的生活，也许
maybe I could DJ and learn you know some
还能当DJ，学习
other things but my I've always said
其他东西。我一直都说，暂停时间会是
that that would that would be my chosen
我选择的
superpower but how does one practically
超能力。但是，怎样才能真正让
slow time down so that 30 years doesn't
时间慢下来，让30年不至于
fly past
飞逝而过呢？
so when you're a dad one of the things
当你成为父亲后，
you realize is you have this image that
你会发现，你脑海中一直有一个画面，一个
belief that your kids are going to be
信念，那就是你的孩子会喜欢
into World War II history and Crossfit
二战历史和Crossfit，
those are the things I'm interested in
这些都是我感兴趣的东西。
and what you find out is kids have their
但你会发现，孩子们有他们
own interests and if you want to be a
自己的兴趣。如果你想成为一个
good dad you have to lean into their
好父亲，就必须顺应他们的
interests otherwise you're just not
兴趣，否则你和
with them because they they're selfish
他们之间就很难建立起牢固的关系，因为他们是自私的，
kids are inherently selfish and they're
孩子们天生就是自私的。 我
oh well Dad's really the World War II
爸对二战
history so I'll go to the you know the
历史特别感兴趣，所以我经常去
the British war museum and I'll find it
英国战争博物馆，觉得特别有意思。但
my kids so yesterday I ended up at
孩子们可不这么想。昨天我去了
life-size Monopoly which is this
真人大小的大富翁游戏，就是那种真人大小的
lifesize Monopoly game somewhere and for
大富翁游戏。对
me that's the seventh ring of hell
我来说，那简直是地狱第七层。不过，为了让
try to do to slow time down is I
时间慢下来，我通常会立刻让自己
immediately go into like okay just
进入“好吧，先别
ignore the thing you know check your
管它，看看
email be a good dad just do get through
邮件，做个好爸爸，赶紧熬过去”的状态。
it get through it I find you can slow
我发现，让自己投入到一些事情中也能让时间慢
time down by getting into stuff like
下来，比如，
trying to like s really try and get in
努力让自己真正投入
get into life-size Monopoly and engage
到真人大小的大富翁游戏中，
with my child and like be a little bit
和孩子一起玩，甚至有点夸张。
over the top about it and when they do
当他们
cheers scream loud like trying just get
欢呼、尖叫的时候，就努力让自己真正投入进去。
really into things because if you want
因为如果你想让
time to pass it will it'll cooperate but
时间流逝，它自然会配合。但当
when you get really into stuff even
你真正投入到某件事中时，
though you think it's stupid and cheesy
即使你觉得它很蠢很俗气，甚至忍不住
and you're like can't help but think God
想“天哪，
this is like Chinese water
这简直就是
torture um I find that slow it down also
酷刑”，我发现这样做也能让时间慢下来。另外，我
find leaning into your emotions slows
发现顺其自然地表达自己的情绪也能让时间慢下来。
time down because it makes you more
时间慢下来，因为它让你更活在
present um I didn't cry or laugh out
当下。嗯，
loud from the ages of 30 to 44 for 14
从30岁到44岁，整整14
years I didn't cry once and I didn't
年，我既没哭也没笑，一次也没哭过，
laugh out loud I for I lost the capacity
因为我失去了
to uncontrollably laugh and to cry I
无法控制地大笑和哭泣的能力，我好像
just kind of forgot how to do either of
忘记了该怎么做。
those things and emotions are things you
情绪是
have to practice so I remember the first
需要练习的，所以我记得第
time I started crying and the first time
一次哭，第一次
I really laughed at loud with friends I
和朋友们开怀大笑，我当时
thought God did both these things feel
想，天哪，这两种感觉都
great and I started getting really into
太棒了。我开始真正沉浸其中，
those things and feeling guilt when I do
当我做了
something stupid or like trying to
蠢事或者试图
really embrace my emotions because that
真正拥抱自己的情绪时，我会感到内疚，因为这
indicates what's important to you what
表明什么对你来说是重要的，什么
moves you what inspires you what upsets
触动你，什么激励你，什么让
you what pisses you off and I find
你难过，什么让你生气。我发现，
emotions like real raw emotions when you
当你
register them and absorb them and like
感知、吸收并
lean into the messy part of yourself I
接纳自己混乱的一面时，那些真实而原始的情绪会
find that slows time down so getting
慢下来，所以沉浸其中，感知
into stuff and registering your emotions
你的情绪。
and as a business person you're taught
作为一个商人，你会被教导要有点
to be a little bit stoic you have this
坚忍，你会有一种
weird sense also as a man of masculinity
奇怪的感觉，作为一个男人，你会觉得
that men don't feel their emotions but
男人应该…… 感受不到他们的情绪，但
you you start forgetting what's
你却开始忘记什么
important to you you start forgetting
对你来说重要，开始忘记
what like is real your things you're
什么是真实的，你的兴趣爱好，比如什么让
into like what what do you find
你觉得
hilarious what makes you well up with
好笑，什么让你感动得
tears because you find it so moving
热泪盈眶。如果你
without being without doing that stuff
不做这些事，
you forget what's important to you you
你就会忘记什么对你来说重要，
forget like you kind of lose your
你会失去你的
individualism uh anyway so there's and
个性。嗯，总之，
you talked to Simon Sy there's a bunch
你和西蒙·施（Simon Sy）谈过，他
of people who have a lot of means uh
有很多钱。嗯，这是
your book the algebra of Happiness the
你的书《幸福的代数》里的两个技巧。
third section is about health and you
第三部分是关于健康的，你
spoke earlier about the importance of it
之前也谈到了健康的重要性。
I've really recently over the last two
我最近
years I'd say learned the importance of
两年才真正意识到
health and make sure I work out pretty
健康的重要性，并且几乎
much every day what are why is health so
每天都锻炼。为什么健康这么
important you know I've I've been on my
重要？你知道，我一直在努力
own journe to understand it but um one
理解它。
of the things you said was that the most
你提到，
common trait among CEOs is that they
CEO们最常见的特点就是他们
regularly um and even think you said you
经常锻炼。你甚至说过
made comments about alcohol being bad
酒精
for us did you did you take time to
对我们有害，你花时间去
learn that I know you've been working
了解了吗？ 我知道你
out since you were very very young MH
从很小的时候就开始锻炼了，MH，
but the the overarching role of our
但是健康在我们生活中扮演着至关重要的角色，
health in everything um what have you
嗯，你
learned about that and the importance of
对此有什么感悟？它的重要性又体现在
it well it's kind of where it all starts
哪里呢？嗯，这可以说是一切的起点。
I mean this is not a rental you know
我的意思是，这不是试镜，你知道，
this is not a tress rehearsal your body
这不是彩排，你的身材
is it I mean you look you you look like
看起来就像
an athlete what do you do every day what
个运动员，对吧？你每天都做什么？
do you thank you I'll clip that um and
谢谢，我会把这段话剪辑下来，
I'll put that in my
放到我的个人
bio um I do a mixture so I I train for
简介里。我做的是混合训练，所以我
an hour every day um jamim is in my
每天都训练一个小时。Jamim 在我的
fitness group so about 90% of days a
健身小组里，所以我们一年中大约 90% 的时间都在
year we we train um yesterday was
训练。昨天是
CrossFit uh yeah yesterday was CrossFit
CrossFit，嗯，是的，昨天是 CrossFit。所以，
so yeah so look if you could do
如果你能做一些
something that would make you less
事情，让你不那么
depressed make you more likely to be
抑郁，更有可能
successful F broaden your selection set
成功，拓宽你的交友范围，
mates I mean wouldn't wouldn't you want
我的意思是，你难道不想
to take that drug every day it's called
每天都服用这种“药物”吗？它叫做
exercise we're happiest as a species in
运动。作为人类，我们在运动中，在人群中，是最快乐的。
motions surrounded by others we've been
我们一直以
hunting and Gathering so the things
狩猎和采集为生。
you're going to remember in your life
你一生中最难忘的事情
are usually not the CrossFit class but
通常不是CrossFit课程，而是
walking around Rome with your family and
和家人、
your kids complaining but being outside
孩子在罗马漫步，听他们抱怨，但和
exercise with people you care about so
你在乎的人一起进行某种形式的户外运动。
uh an exercise and feeling strong uh I
运动，感觉强壮，这对我
mean it's been my anti-depressant if I
来说就像抗抑郁药。如果我
don't you know I got here four three
不运动，你知道，我四三天前才到这里，
four days ago I've only worked out once
只锻炼过一次，
I can feel myself I'm angrier I'm not as
我就会感觉自己更生气，没那么
nice I don't feel as good about myself
友善，对自己也没那么满意。
it's I think for a lot of people it is
我认为对很多人来说，运动
it is the easiest means to an
是最简单的
anti-depressant it's the closest thing
抗抑郁方法，它最接近
we have to a youth serum you have this
青春灵药。
your brain trying to figure out if
你的大脑里基本上有一个24小时不间断的监控摄像头，试图判断
you're adding value that's the bad news
你是否在创造价值。这是坏消息。
the good news is it's got terrible res
好消息是，它的检测能力很差，
solution and you can fool it so if
你可以骗过它。所以，如果
you're caring for other people
你在照顾别人，
caregivers generally live longer because
照顾者通常会更长寿，因为
your brain will sense that you're caring
你的大脑会感知到你在照顾
for other people you're social you're
别人，你在社交，你在与
touching people you're concerned and it
人接触，你在关心别人，它会
releases a hormone that lets you stay
释放压力。 一种能让你活下去的激素，
alive new mothers typically do not die
新妈妈通常不会死。
um if you're exercising intensely it
嗯，如果你进行高强度运动，它会
fools the camera into believing that
欺骗摄像头，让它以为
you're hunting prey or building housing
你在狩猎或建造房屋，
and it says let's keep this person
然后它会说，让我们把这个人留得更
around longer so it is a great
久一些。所以它是一种很好的
anti-depressant it's a great use serum
抗抑郁药，一种很棒的血清。
um I find you're just Kinder you're
嗯，我发现你会更
nicer you're more confident so you know
友善、更和蔼、更自信。所以你知道，
it's I again uh the thing that the
我又说了，
Fortune 500 cosos have most in common
财富500强公司最共同的一点，
it's not the schools they went to it's
不是他们上的学校，甚至
not even their it's not even their
不是他们的
ethnicity it is gender only 483 of them
种族，而是性别。其中只有483位
are men but more than any practice or
是男性，但比起任何习惯或
attribute it's that they work out four
特质，最重要的是他们每周锻炼四
to five times plus a week physical
到五次以上。体能
fitness again it's one of my
训练，这是我的一个
algorithms you should not watch other
算法。你不应该花
people sweat for any longer than you
比自己锻炼更多的时间去看别人流汗。
sweat and I you
你
know if if you're watching other people
知道，如果你每周看别人
sweat four hours a week and you're
流汗四个小时，而自己每周只
sweating one hour a week you're in
流汗一个小时，那就
trouble do not you have to sweat more
麻烦了。你不需要
than you watch other people sweat the
比看别人流汗的时间流汗更多。
other thing we have in common is um our
我们还有另一点…… 我们共同的
backgrounds in advertising and brand you
背景是广告和品牌。
you speak a lot about um branding and
您经常谈到品牌和
advertising um I sat here with Rory
广告。我和罗里·
Sutherland and that was one of our real
萨瑟兰一起录制了一期节目，那是我们
best performing episodes I didn't
收视率最高的节目之一。我之前并没有
realize there was such a demand on from
意识到
our audience in terms of practical
我们的观众对实用
advertising knowledge he talked a lot
广告知识的需求如此之高。他谈了很多
about Apple and Tesla and the secrets
关于苹果和特斯拉以及它们的成功秘诀。
building a reputation changed in your
在您的一生中，广告和品牌建设的格局发生了怎样的变化？
thing for Brands to understand now or
品牌要想成功，现在最重要的是理解什么？或者说，
some of the important things for Brands
品牌要想成功，有哪些重要的事情需要
to understand now if they are to be
理解？我
successful yeah so my first job in
在商学院的第一份工作是
business school I started a company
创办了一家
called profit brand strategy that's now
名为“利润品牌战略”（Profit Brand Strategy）的公司，
about 500 people now it's just called
现在大约有500名员工，公司简称“
profit and the basic notion was it was
利润”（Profit）。公司的基本理念是
based on the principles of my professor
基于
my second year David 's considered the
我二年级教授大卫·萨瑟兰的理论。他被认为是
father of modern branding and it was
现代品牌之父，他认为
brand or set of products or services are
品牌或一系列产品或服务所蕴含的无形联想是
the only sustainable
唯一可持续的
advantage that if you can wrap a set of
优势。如果你能将一系列
products and services with these brand
产品和服务与这些品牌
codes of masculinity European Elegance
符号——例如阳刚之气、欧式优雅、
Youth and then pound away at those
青春活力——结合起来，那么……
associations using this incredibly chap
利用广播广告这种极其
cheap efficient medium called broadcast
廉价高效的媒介，不断强化这些关联性。
advertising you can take a marginal shoe
你可以把一双平庸的鞋子、一份
salty snack marginal car and get amazing
咸味零食、一辆平庸的汽车，变成利润惊人的商品。这就是
the from the end of World War II to the
从二战结束到
introduction of Google in the 90s the
90年代谷歌出现以来，
algorithm for creating massive
创造巨额
shareholder wealth was find a mediocre
股东财富的算法：找到一款平庸的
product wrap it in amazing brand codes
产品，用惊艳的品牌包装起来，
and make people feel more patriotic or
让人们感觉更爱国、
more or younger stuff the Channel with
更年轻，然后通过各种渠道推广，
it and print money the pgs the Pepsi Co
印钞机就能赚到大钱。
of the world you know the coca-colas
百事可乐、可口可乐，
these were the economic Titans of yester
这些昔日的经济巨头，如今早已过时。
because our weapons of diligence whether
因为我们现在的“勤奋武器”，无论
it's Google or trip advis or Amazon
是谷歌、TripAdvisor还是亚马逊
reviews now gets us to the best product
评论，都能让我们找到最好的产品，
without the benefit of this weapon of
而无需借助
diligence called brand when I come came
品牌这种“勤奋武器”。我以前来
to London I used to stay at the Four
伦敦的时候，住在
Seasons in the mandin Oriental why
四季酒店或文华东方酒店，
because someone else was paying and
因为有人付钱，而且
their old was an eight and then I went
他们的评分是8分。后来我
on trip advisor and I went on my social
上了TripAdvisor，又看了看我的社交
graph and I found out the people love
关系，发现
the conet hotel or people love the
人们喜欢康奈特酒店或芬
Ferndale hotels I I started staying at
代尔酒店。 我开始住在
the Hay Market why I like a place from a
海伊市场酒店，因为我喜欢那里，附近有
nice gym and I want to pay stay at with
不错的健身房，而且我想住在能和
cooler than me so I started staying at
比我年轻、更酷的人一起玩的地方。所以我开始住
boutique hotels so all of a sudden
精品酒店。突然之间，
product became the bomb again and then
产品又成了热门话题，
your ability to embrace these new
你驾驭
mediums around social became more
社交媒体等新媒介的能力变得
important than broadcast advertising so
比传统广告更重要。因此，
the traditional metrics of branding the
传统的品牌推广指标、
brand identity and broadcast advertising
品牌识别和传统广告渠道——
that I've been preaching in brand
我一直在品牌
strategy the sun has passed midday if
战略中强调的这些——已经过时了。如果
you look at my curriculum and the
你看看我的课程以及
majority of curriculums and marketing
大多数课程和市场营销
departments You could argue that we're
部门，你可能会说我们
just training people to go to work at
只是在培养人们去
Unilever or General Mills and be laid
联合利华或通用磨坊工作，然后
off 24 months
24个月
later uh branding has become much more
后被解雇。现在，品牌推广更多地
about Innovation and actual product
关注创新和实际的产品
quality now that extends into how you
质量，这延伸到你如何
discover the product how you absorb the
发现产品、如何吸收
product the community around it but you
产品以及围绕产品的社群。你
know Tesla is a better product Apple
知道，特斯拉现在的产品更好了。苹果
used to be an underpowered product with
以前是一个性能不足但品牌很棒的产品，
a great brand now it's a great brand
现在它是一个拥有卓越产品的伟大品牌。Airbnb
is a much better product these things
现在的产品也更好了。谷
are G Google is 10x better than what was
歌比
there before it so supply
以前好十倍。供应
chain uh design the way you absorb the
链也是如此。 呃，设计就是你吸收
product its ease of use you know it's
产品的方式，它的易用性。你知道，它已经
just it's moved from kind of what you
从
call a brand economy to for back lack of
所谓的品牌经济，或者更确切地说，
a better term an innovation economy so
创新经济，转变了。所以，与其去上
Advertising I say take classes on supply
广告课，不如去上供应
chain or analytics or really understand
链、数据分析或者真正理解
industrial design you know there was a
工业设计的课。你知道，以前人们
general feeling that all product quality
普遍认为所有产品质量都达到了极限，
and then the internet came along and
然后互联网出现了，
unlocked all this product Innovation so
释放了所有产品创新。比如
cars they felt that hit kind of a peak
汽车，人们觉得汽车的
in terms of product quality and then all
产品质量已经达到了顶峰，然后
of a sudden with the internet and GPS
突然之间，有了互联网和GPS，
you could you could tune a car up uh
你可以无线调校汽车，你
wirelessly you you can unlock the doors
可以无线解锁车门，你可以用它做
uh there was all kinds of crazy things
各种各样疯狂的事情。
in addition to EV I mean there's just
除了电动汽车，我的意思是，
been so much actual Innovation around
围绕产品本身已经涌现出了大量的创新。
valuable companies in the world have in
世界上最有价值的公司有什么
common they either spend no money on
共同点？它们要么不花钱
advertising or they're spending less
做广告，要么减少广告支出。
Apple's the strongest brand in the world
苹果是世界上最强大的品牌，
at least a consumer brand I would argue
至少在消费品牌方面是这样。我认为
the strongest mans in the world
世界上最强大的品牌是
universities but it's
大学，但它已经将
reallocated six or seven billion dollars
六七十亿美元的广告预算从
out of broadcast advertising into its
广播电视重新分配出去。 苹果公司通过
channel into stores so buildt 550
渠道向实体店投放广告，打造了550
temples to the brand and I think of that
家品牌旗舰店。我认为这
as almost part of the product my
几乎是产品本身的一部分。
12-year-old and I were bored yesterday
昨天我和我12岁的孩子闲着无聊，
so we went to the Apple Store so that's
就去了苹果商店。这其实也算是
kind of consuming the product and I end
一种消费。我
up buying screen savers and new cases
最后买了屏幕保护膜和新手机壳，这些东西的
margin that I could find a fck or Best
毛利率肯定有90%，我肯定能在百思
Buy or someone for less money but we
买之类的商店找到更便宜的，但我们就是
want to be in that store and in that
想去那家店，体验那种
environment so it's it's moving out of
氛围。所以，苹果正在从
pre- purchase broadcast advertising into
售前广播广告转向
the distribution Channel and into
分销渠道，并进行
Innovation but the
创新。但
traditional the traditional Norms of
传统的
marketing or branding as I taught it
营销或品牌推广模式，就像我以前教的那样，已经过时了。
that shit's over Don Draper has been
唐·德雷珀（Don Draper）已经被
drawn and quartered if you're watching a
五马分尸了。如果你看了
lot of advertising it means your life
很多广告，那就说明你的生活
hasn't worked out the majority of people
不太顺利。现在，大多数
who are technically literate
懂技术
or um uh wealthy can avoid 80 90% of
或者比较富裕的人可以避开80%到90%的
advertising now they watch Netflix they
广告。他们看Netflix，
they subscribe to Spotify they live in
订阅Spotify，住在
cities where they have uh local
有地方
officials that demand you can't see a
官员要求禁止
billboard from a
广告牌的城市里。 从公园里说起，
so advertising is a tax on the poor and
广告是对穷人和
the technologically illiterate so it's
科技文盲的一种征税，所以它
moved to more distribution and
转向了更多的分销和
Innovation but for God's sakes don't you
创新。但是，看在上帝的份上，难道你不想
know avoid the of falling into the Trap
避免落入“
Universe are branders or
宇宙的主宰是品牌商或广告
advertisers if they are innovators then
商”的陷阱吗？如果他们是创新者，那么
how does one make make themselves or
如何让自己或
their team more Innovative this is the
团队更具创新力呢？这是
question I get asked all the time yeah
我经常被问到的问题。是的，
when I speak at conferences or to
当我在会议上或对企业演讲时，人们会问：
how do we make our 500 people in our
我们如何让公司里的500名员工进行
company in innovate because you'll see
创新？因为你会看到
the CEO standing you know in front of
CEO站在
the the board meeting on or the the All
董事会或全体
Hands and say we need to be more
员工大会上说，我们需要更具
Innovative yeah what does that mean
创新力。是啊，那是什么意思？
right does [__] all we all know that but
我们都知道，但
by Design how how do we create an
通过设计，我们该如何培养
Innovative mindset ourselves or
自己或团队的创新思维？
teams that's a tough one I don't
这真是个难题。我不
consider myself um an expert on culture
认为自己是文化方面的专家，
although it's clearly out there like I
尽管这方面的知识显然存在。比如
think of HBO HBO if there's a show that
HBO，如果有什么节目在
people are talking about I don't know if
人们谈论，我并不认为它是文化方面的专家。 不知道是不是也
the same is true but in the US people
一样，但在美国，
are talking if there's a show people are
如果有什么剧集成为人们
talking about the water cooler it's
茶余饭后的谈资，那就是《亢奋》（
Euphoria it's
Euphoria）或《
succession it's generally an HBO show
继承之战》（Succession），通常都是HBO的剧集。HBO的
budget of some of the other streaming
预算只有其他一些流媒体
networks so there's something about that
平台的三分之一左右，所以这种
culture where they're able to come up
文化让他们能够创作出
with kind of
一些
breakthrough creative some companies
突破性的创意作品。有些公司似乎总能
just seem to do that time and time again
做到这一点，没错。
agreed and so it's a culture thing at
所以，归根结底，这是一种文化现象，即使是
the heart of it even Apple you you know
苹果公司也是如此，
yeah especially under the ear of Steve
尤其是在史蒂夫·乔布斯的领导下，
Jobs they seem to take some unbelievably
他们似乎敢于进行一些令人难以置信的冒险尝试，而且这些
scary um bets that paid off obviously a
尝试都获得了回报。当然，
lot of them don't some of them don't but
很多尝试并没有成功，有些则不然。但
Amazon's the same AWS the Kindle 100%
亚马逊也是如此，AWS和Kindle的成功率是100%。
yeah so you know I mean you know there's
所以，你知道，这其中有
some Basics it's a willingness to fail
一些基本要素：愿意承担失败的风险，敢于进行
to take big bets to reward people for
大胆的尝试，并奖励那些
taking risks I think an external
承担风险的人。我认为，
Viewpoint that's constantly benchmarking
不断地对标
other companies I mean my last reml to
其他公司也是一个重要的外部视角。我最后要说的是，
essentially what we did was we went out
我们所做的就是对标
every company in Social e-commerce
所有社交电商领域的最佳实践。
payments and then came in and said okay
付款之后，他们进来，说好的，
unil lever okay Nike what can you learn
Unil Lever，好的，耐克，你能从
from everyone from Adidas to Tata Motors
阿迪达斯到塔塔汽车等所有公司学到什么？
like what are they doing that's really
比如，他们在做什么？这真的很
interesting so having an external
有意思。所以，拥有外部
Viewpoint a willing to take big bats I
视角，愿意承担风险，我
also think holding people accountable
也认为追究责任的
found businesses seem to to be much more
企业似乎更有
Innovative obviously I think they they
创新精神。显然，我认为它们
often fail quicker as well but they seem
失败得也更快，但它们似乎
to have a higher risk appetite than
比传统企业有更高的风险承受能力。
fered businesses we have a closing
我们
tradition on this podcast right where
这个播客有个结尾的传统，就在……
the last guest leaves a question for the
最后一位客人给下一位客人留了一个问题，
next guest they don't know who they're
他们不知道是留给谁的，我得
it until I open the
打开
book
书才能看到。
um the question that's been left for you
嗯，留给你的问题，
okay do I get to know who left it you
好吧，我能知道是谁留的吗？你
don't I don't oh no
不知道。我不知道。哦，不。
okay what is your biggest regret
好吧，你个人最大的遗憾是什么？
personally and if you could go back what
如果可以回到过去，
would you do
你会做些什么
differently it's funny it's the
不同的事情？有趣的是，这些
questions that are obvious over the
问题其实很显而易见。
heart my biggest
我个人最大的
regret
遗憾是，我
personally I wish I had been Kinder from
希望自己从小就更善良。
an earlier age I think it's good for the
我认为这对
world I think it makes me feel more
世界有益，我认为这让我感觉更有
masculine it makes me feel more
男子气概，让我感觉更
successful to be kind and I didn't
成功。我并不是偶然发现这一点的，
stumble upon that I wish i' i' come to
我希望自己能
sooner that to be generous to be loving
早点意识到这一点，那就是慷慨、充满爱心……
friend of mine says that the the most
我的朋友辛迪·加洛普说过，最
wasted resource is good intentions I
浪费的资源是善意。我
wish my good intentions had I was more
希望我的善意能够更充分地被利用。我更愿意、
ready more confident to articulate the
更自信地表达
kind thoughts I had about others and to
我对别人的善意，并且
articulate them with more ease I've
更轻松地表达出来。我曾经
thought good things about other people
想过别人的好话，
I've wanted to do good things for a long
我…… 我一直想做好事，
time but I didn't have the confidence or
但我既没有自信也没有
the discipline to either say them or do
自律去说出来或去做。
them I wish I'd had that confidence
我真希望自己能早点拥有这份自信，
earlier because the majority of us are
因为我们大多数人都是
good people the majority of us admire
好人，我们大多数人都欣赏别人，
other people the majority of us love
我们大多数人都爱
other people and we don't want to
别人，但我们却不愿
articulate it I think especially men
表达出来。我想尤其是男人，
because we're worried that saying I
因为我们担心说“我
admire you or you know you're just such
欣赏你”或者“你知道吗，你真是个
a handsome young buff man who's who's
英俊健壮的年轻男人，
acquired so much success at a young age
年纪轻轻就取得了如此多的成功，
I'm kind of like trying to figure out
我其实很想知道，
I'd love to know like how did you do all
你是怎么做到的？”
embarrassing for a man there's this
对男人来说，说这些话会很尴尬。
feeling among men that me saying that
男人之间有一种感觉，觉得我说这些话会显得
makes me less successful and masculine
自己不够成功，不够有男子气概，
like it's a zero sum game and what you
好像这是个零和博弈。但随着年龄的增长，你会
realize as you get older is that is that
意识到，表达这些才是
is how you feel strong and how you feel
你感到强大和
kind I wish I'd figured that out earlier
善良的方式。我真希望自己能早点明白这一点，
I wish I'd been more forth coming with
我希望自己能更坦诚地表达
my positive
积极的
emotions does that end up making us
情绪。这样做最终会不会让我们自己感到
miserable personally so if I if I have
痛苦呢？如果我有这种感觉，那几乎…… 这是一种
resentment isn't it we I think we all
怨恨，不是吗？我想我们都有。
have it I think when Justin Bieber came
我记得贾斯汀·比伯刚出道的时候，
onto the scene and I looked over and
我看到一个大概
there was this like 14-year-old that had
14岁的男孩，身边
all the women and he was beautiful and
美女环绕，演唱
he was selling out these Arenas I'm
会场场爆满，当时我
thinking [__] it this guy well shadon
就想，去他的，这家伙……嗯，就像沙登·
Freud I mean it's just resentment of
弗洛伊德说的那样，这只是对
other people's success I think that's
别人成功的怨恨。我觉得这不
different I think I think Justin Bieber
一样，贾斯汀·比伯确实有点被人
worn some hate um but for sure but the
憎恨，嗯，但肯定的是，
reason I I was hating on him was purely
我讨厌他的原因纯粹是
jealousy it was fair enough but I my
嫉妒，这很正常。但我的
sense is you seem pretty self-actualized
感觉是，你这个年纪似乎已经很自我实现了。
at your age I was at the age of 30 as an
我30岁的时候，作为一名
entrepreneur if my team was doing a
企业家，如果我的团队表现
great job and there was a great
出色，并且有一个很棒的
shot I rewarded them at the end of the
项目，我会在年底给他们
bonus as you get older what you realize
奖金。随着年龄的增长，你会意识到
is young people need watering it doesn't
年轻人需要鼓励，不管
matter how successful they are it
他们多么成功，
doesn't have much money they're making
赚的钱不多。
when you say I sent a text this morning
比如，你今天早上发了条短信，
we did a my prop G has this this new
我们做了……我的Prompt G有这个新
thing called we have something called a
东西。 我们有个叫“
markets podcast which is focused on the
市场播客”的东西，专门讨论
markets the team did such an amazing job
市场。团队
with the sound edits today and it's a
今天在音效剪辑方面做得非常出色，而且这还是个
24y old it's a 24y old doing this [__]
24岁的女孩做的，她才24岁，却很
and she has such a feel and name is CLA
有感觉。她叫CLA
Miller she has such a feel for how to
Miller，她对如何
integrate Sound and Music and knows when
融合音效和音乐有着敏锐的感知，知道什么时候
to fade it in and fade it out and I
淡入淡出。我
immediately registered that and I think
立刻就注意到了这一点，我觉得
oh me registering that is really good
我注意到这一点
for her because I'm the boss well why
对她来说真的很好，因为我是老板。为什么
wouldn't you pull out your phone phone
不拿出手机告诉她：“你在
and say your integration of sound here
这里的音效融合
is so striking and your talent is so
太棒了，你的才华
ahead of where you are and I did that
远超你的年龄！” 我就这么做了。
and I know when she wakes up this
我知道她今天
morning and gets that text message it's
早上醒来收到这条短信时，一定会非常感动，一定会非常感动。
to make her mourning 20 years ago I
20年前我
didn't think to do that why I don't know
没想到要这么做，我也不知道为什么，就是没想到，就是没想到。也许是因为
know selfish didn't want to give up that
自私，不想
again S as somewhat of lazy not kind I
再次放弃，或者说有点懒惰，而不是善良。我
don't know is there an element of
不知道，是不是因为
thinking that if you give the compliment
这样想的…… 你夸奖
then someone can
别人，别人可能会
become complacent or they can become
变得自满，或者
they might not strive as hard maybe I
不再那么努力。我
don't know I saw my job as a CEO back
不知道。我以前当CEO的时候，感觉自己无时无刻不在管着
was um all over everybody all of the
所有人，
time I mean just all the time and I'm
我是说真的，无时无刻不在管着所有人。现在我还是这样，虽然没以前那么严重了，但
as well to be fair and look there's
公平地说，还是有点儿。你看，
that's you can do that and still be kind
你可以做到这样，同时又保持友善。
I was on a panel with other CEOs and
我之前参加过一个CEO小组讨论，
they asked what is your management
他们问我的管理理念是什么。
philosophy and this one woman who runs a
其中一位经营着一家
very successful uh startup said it's
非常成功的创业公司的女士说，管理理念是
putting people in the role to succeed
让员工在合适的岗位上取得成功。
and the other one and the other person
另一位CEO则
said it's it's helping people find their
说，管理理念是帮助员工找到
true self finding what they're really
真正的自我，找到他们真正
passionate about and then they came to
热爱的事业。然后她们对
me like I'm all [__] over everybody
我说，我无时无刻不在管着所有人，
all of the [__] time and every you
你
know I just went I'm like I don't know
知道吗？我当时就想，我不知道还能怎么
how else to do it I'm just all over and
做，我就是管得太多。
I realized maybe that's why I've never
我意识到，也许这就是我一直没
been able to grow a billion dollar
能打造出十亿美元
business cuz I'm just to I don't want
企业的原因，因为我太……我不想
say in the weeds I do give people uh I
说我事无巨细地管着所有人。 我觉得应该给人们
think a decent amount of latitude but I
一定的自由度，但我
don't know how else to do it just to you
不知道还能怎么做，就是不能事事都管着，
of the time I I don't maybe that's why
我可能……也许这就是为什么
again I don't I'm not running a
我又不这么做的原因。我又不是在经营一家价值数
multi-billion dollar
十亿美元的
franchise I can
连锁店。我能
relate I can relate
理解，我能理解，
um I can relate to that a lot but that's
嗯，我非常能理解，但这
a conversation for another time I guess
我想以后再聊吧，
because it's not as much about me but
因为这跟我关系不大。不过，
thank you Scott for your time and your
斯科特，谢谢你抽出时间分享你的
wisom I followed you for some time and I
智慧。我关注你一段时间了，我
remember going out to Barley a couple of
记得几年前去巴利（Barley）的时候，
years ago grabbing the book in the
在机场买了你的书，
airport when I was off to write my own
当时我要去写自己的
book so I your book was a source of
书。所以你的书给了我很多
inspiration for me I remember reading on
灵感。我记得当时在
my desk there in Uber um and that's why
优步（Uber）的桌子上读你的书，嗯，所以
today but I guess it's upstairs and your
今天没看到它让我很惊讶。不过我想它应该在楼上吧。你
your [__] free approach to sharing
坦诚地分享
yourself and your ideas is is incredibly
自己和自己的想法，这种方式非常
important we I think we've seen a sort
重要。我觉得我们已经看到，人们越来越不愿意袒露心扉，
vulnerable um and brutally honest about
也不愿意对
our perspectives and doesn't mean our
自己的观点坦诚相待。 这并不意味着我们的
perspectives are always correct but but
观点总是正确的，但
honest I think is how we ultimately lead
我认为，两种真诚想法的碰撞最终会引领我们走向
to progress so I love that and that's
进步，所以我很喜欢这一点，这也是
why we ultimately have this podcast your
我们最终推出这个播客的原因。你的
new book a drift America and 100 charts
新书《漂移的美国与100张图表》
is out now yep why did you write that
现在已经出版了。是的，你为什么会写这
book of all the things you you know you
本书呢？你知道，你对
know so much about so many things and
很多事情都了如指掌，也
you talk about so many topics why that
谈论过很多话题，为什么会选择这
book um I'm fascinated with the idea of
本书呢？嗯，我对
a nation and connective tissue I feel
国家和连接组织的概念
very patriotic as I get older I'm more
很感兴趣。随着年龄的增长，我越来越爱国，也越来越
grateful for my blessings and one of my
感激我所拥有的一切。
blessings I talked about was being born
我谈到的其中一项恩赐就是出生
in America and I wanted uh I love charts
在美国。我喜欢图表。
since the alphabet for 1500 years but
自从字母出现以来，我们已经用文字交流了1500年，但
we've been communicating with images
我们也一直在用图像交流，
whether it was reading them off the cave
无论是解读
cave walls or the walls of caves or
洞穴墙壁上的文字，还是
looking at the height of the sun and the
观察太阳和天空的高度，这种交流方式已经持续了
sky for tens of thousands so I've always
数万年。所以我一直
been really drawn to charts we can
很喜欢图表。视觉
process information 6 to 60 times faster
信息的处理速度可以提高6到60倍，
when it's visual so I thought how can I
所以我思考：如何才能…… 我
create a narrative around what Al's
围绕着“艾尔的
America and what are some of the
美国”以及一些
solutions with charts so it's a chart
解决方案，用图表构建了一个叙事。所以，图表
and then a narrative second chart and a
和叙事交替出现，
narrative all grouped into themes and
最终都归纳成不同的主题。
also I just want to write a book every
我还想每隔
12 to 15 months I feel like it's the
12到15个月写一本书。我觉得这是
hardest thing I do but I feel like it
我做过的最难的事情，但它让
keeps me sort of young and some of those
我保持年轻。这些
narratives are conversations we've had
叙事中有些内容是我们
today but explained in more context um
今天讨论过的，只是在更广阔的背景下进行了解释。嗯，
and all of your books books have been
你的所有作品对
important for me it's because of the way
我来说都很重要，因为
that you write oh thanks it's not it's
你的写作方式。哦，谢谢。
not just the content itself but it's
不仅仅是内容本身，而是你用
writing in such an accessible way which
如此通俗易懂的方式写作，这使得像
accessible to someone like me who is not
我这样不具备任何知识背景的人也能理解非常复杂的主题。
I don't consider myself to be an
我并不认为自己是
intellectual in any capacity and thank
知识分子。感谢
you for your time today uh it's a real
你今天抽出时间。
Stroke of Luck that you now live in
你现在住在
London and you're able to be here and do
伦敦，能够来到这里做
this and I feel very honored that you
这件事，真是太幸运了。我感到非常荣幸你能
came so thank you I appreciate that
来，谢谢你，我很感激。
congratulations on all your success
祝贺你取得的所有成就。
thank you so much Scott it's a pleasure
非常感谢你，斯科特。 很高兴听到
quick word from one of our sponsors I've
一位赞助商的消息。我
got a tip for all of you that will make
有个小技巧要分享给大家，它能让
your virtual meeting experiences I think
你们的虚拟会议体验提升
10 times better as some of you may know
十倍。可能有些人已经知道，
by now Blue Jeans by Verizon offers
Verizon 的 Blue Jeans 提供
seamless high quality video conferencing
流畅的高质量视频会议。
but the reason why I use blue jeans
我之所以选择 Blue Jeans 而不是
versus other video conferencing tools is
其他视频会议工具，是
because of immersion their tools make
因为它能带来沉浸式体验。Blue Jeans 的工具能让
you feel more connected to the employees
你感觉与员工或客户之间的联系更加紧密。
with and now they're launching one of
现在，他们推出了迄今为止
their biggest feature enhancements to
最重要的功能增强之一——Blue Jean Studio，旨在
impact virtual events so far called Blue
提升虚拟活动体验。
Jean Studio I actually used it the other
前几天我试用了 Blue Jean Studio，
day I did a virtual event using the
用它举办了一场虚拟活动。活动时长
studio which I think about 700 you came
大约 700 分钟，达到了
to TV level production quality all done
电视级别的制作质量，而且所有操作都由
by one person with very little technical
一位技术经验不多的人用
experience on a laptop so if you've got
笔记本电脑完成。所以，如果你即将举办
an event coming up and you're thinking
活动，并且正在考虑
about doing it virtually check out blue
线上举办，那就赶紧去了解一下 Blue
jean studio now let me know what you
Jean Studio 吧！告诉我你的
think because I genuinely believe I know
想法。我知道
this is an advert and I'm supposed to
这是个广告，我应该
say this but I genuinely believe it's
这么说，但我真心认为它是
production virtual events there is a
目前为止我见过的最好的工具，能够打造真正沉浸式、简单易用且高质量的虚拟活动。  H公司即将推出一款令人
really exciting new product coming from
兴奋的新产品，
H which the founder Julian told me about
创始人Julian
yesterday on WhatsApp um and it's
昨天在WhatsApp上告诉我了。这正是
something I've wanted from H for a long
我一直以来梦寐以求的H产品。
time because when I look at my kind of
因为当我审视自己
and consume every single day to keep me
每天摄入的营养组合时，为了保持
performing at my best and in a good
最佳
shape and healthy there's one thing
状态和健康体魄，我发现其中缺少一样东西，而这恰恰是
missing which you'll currently don't do
你们目前所缺乏的。
yesterday and to know it's on it on its
昨天收到Julian的消息，得知这款产品即将面世，我感到
way is tremendously exciting the thing
无比激动。H的理念在于
about hu is they always focus on a
始终坚持
couple of core principles which is
几个核心原则：
making sure that the the stuff inside
确保
the products are not only nutritionally
产品成分不仅营养
complete but they're sourced from
全面，而且原料均来自
suppliers that provide the best quality
提供最优质营养的供应商。
nutritions and to know that H now going
得知H现在将产品线扩展
into more categories that are essential
到更多
to my nutrition stack is incredibly
对我营养组合至关重要的类别，我感到非常
exciting so if you're starting your hu
兴奋。所以，无论你是刚刚开始你的H之
Journey or you haven't started your hu
旅，还是还没有开始，我都
Journey my recommendation is to get the
建议你先购买
starter pack they have on the website
他们网站上的入门套装（
I'll link it down below and that gives
链接在下方）。入门套装包含
you a little bit of all the products in
所有产品，
a box and then from that you can decide
你可以从中选择适合
which products are for you and where
自己的产品。
they fit in your life and I think if
融入你的生活，我想如果
you're anything like me you might just
你和我一样，你可能会
fall in love with the brand
爱上这个品牌
oh
哦
[Music]
[音乐]